<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Blogopolis - Blogposting</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://tvc-16.science/feeds/blogposting.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://tvc-16.science/</id><updated>2025-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The cozy alternate Internet of GlobalTalk</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/globaltalk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2025-03-22:/globaltalk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;the lengths you have to go through to have fun on the computer these days, i tell you what&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's March! That means Spring is coming in, but also &lt;a href="https://www.marchintosh.com/"&gt;MARCHintosh&lt;/a&gt;, 
the month-long event dedicated to vintage Macs.&lt;br&gt;
And alongside it, so is the &lt;strong&gt;GlobalTalk&lt;/strong&gt; network!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GlobalTalk basically consists of using pre-Internet, vintage Apple networking &lt;strong&gt;grossly beyond its initial spec&lt;/strong&gt; 
to connect dozens of old Macintosh computers&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; together, 
&lt;a href="https://biosrhythm.com/?p=2767"&gt;using the Internet as a bridge&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed out on the fun last year, but this time I got a few of my &lt;a href="./adbuino-ps2.html"&gt;trashpicked&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="./emac-lcd-mod.html"&gt;machines&lt;/a&gt; online.&lt;br&gt;
If we're still in March as you're reading this, you can just go and &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/difegue.tvc-16.science/post/3lk54yua2ww2d"&gt;connect to them right now!&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mac OS 9 screenshot showing a shared folder from a Centris 650 with the classic naviGator icon" src="images/globaltalk/globaltalk.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now, what can you actually do when you're on GlobalTalk?&lt;br&gt;
Well... the networking standard in use, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleTalk"&gt;AppleTalk&lt;/a&gt;, doesn't really allow you to do much!&lt;br&gt;
From your &lt;em&gt;Zone&lt;/em&gt;, you can share local folders from Macs on your network, alongside printers&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So GlobalTalk is &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; just an interconnected net of shared folders, with printers you can print to remotely.&lt;br&gt;
It's as close to &lt;strong&gt;"primordial Internet"&lt;/strong&gt; as you can get and feels a bit &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=afFOMVO3unM"&gt;Battle Network-esque&lt;/a&gt; in a way?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;em&gt;jack in&lt;/em&gt; to a user's AppleTalk Zone, and get to look at the files and programs he's left there for you to look at.&lt;br&gt;
Maybe fuck around and send some memes to his printer, or drop a file into a folder he left write access on.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91044923/watching-susan-kare-explain-the-mac-ux-in-1984-is-the-most-relaxing-thing-ever"&gt;user-oriented interface&lt;/a&gt; of the classic Mac OS accentuates this feeling a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; -- It's incredibly easy to customize the names, icons and positions of every single file in your Zone, so every user's tiny network ends up looking very personal.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, do you know of &lt;strong&gt;any other network&lt;/strong&gt; where you can just fullscreen Big Challenges smoking the boof&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in the File Explorer as a set of 34 custom icons glued to one another??&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Another Mac OS 9 screenshot, showing TalkCrawler indexing a bunch of AppleTalk zones and a shared folder with... Big Challenges smoking the boof! hell yeah!" src="images/globaltalk/talkcrawler.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can just spend &lt;strong&gt;hours&lt;/strong&gt; looking through the Zone list, connecting to different oldass computers across the world named "&lt;em&gt;Glorbo's death star Performa 600&lt;/em&gt;", where they're sharing a pack of Simpsons icons and a text file saying  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hello! thank you for visiting computer  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that took you 30 seconds to open at 64k speed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's...fun! There's a real sense of discovery here caused by the limitations and customizability of it all.  &lt;br&gt;
You can &lt;strong&gt;have fun &lt;em&gt;browsing through things on the computer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which is essentially impossible nowadays on real web browsers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And despite this being a relatively small network all things considered, the variety is still pretty impressive to me.&lt;br&gt;
There are lots of vintage programs, obviously, but also &lt;a href="https://anticapitalist.party/@ahihi/114206693858413006"&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href="https://social.europlus.zone/@europlus/114125705720284399"&gt;art pieces&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
A bloody &lt;em&gt;scavenger hunt&lt;/em&gt; done through printers and files hidden in various zones?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="I now have a moral obligation to kept my sharezone online as it's being used as part of a puzzle how did this even come to be" src="images/globaltalk/ScavengerHunt.jpg"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
In the current age of the &lt;a href="./total-internet-hyperdeath.html"&gt;Total Internet Hyperdeath&lt;/a&gt; caused by the slow coalescing of users onto a handful of massive corporately-owned social platforms that are all turning fascist in one way or another...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GlobalTalk is &lt;strong&gt;punk&lt;/strong&gt; as hell in comparison.&lt;br&gt;
Despite the Internet basically crumbling under its own rot, it's still possible to use it to build people-focused and people-driven communities, and I think that's pretty cool.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, should we actually &lt;code&gt;RETVRN&lt;/code&gt; to AppleTalk? No.... it's &lt;em&gt;really slow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
But I'd say it's worth &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1pXMjrAF5vC08TamkdSt2oFCrDFMP47i5dYcjshn9JzU/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;checking out&lt;/a&gt; if you can. You don't necessarily have to use a vintage Mac either!&lt;br&gt;
Lots of people are using VMs and/or purpose-written software instead.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="*duke nukem voice* those alien bastards have transed their gender! good for them i say" src="images/globaltalk/visited.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;     (visited.jpg, received in the Dropbox of the TVC-16 Zone on GlobalTalk)&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Or things that pretend to be Macintosh computers! There are QEMU emulated macs, Linux machines through &lt;code&gt;netatalk&lt;/code&gt;, Windows 95 machines, &lt;a href="https://mastodon.social/@oevl/114196246218250463"&gt;NeXTStep&lt;/a&gt;... even brand new routers written in Go. &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; which might or might not be an actual physical 1990s printer they're keeping alive through sheer force of will? I have no idea how they do it, printers are hell... I should mention there are also some programs that actually support AppleTalk networking, so you can use a few games and &lt;a href="https://bitbang.social/@kalleboo/114193676799421822"&gt;chat programs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; The OG big challenges boof artwork can be found &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/squeakitties.bsky.social/post/3ljx7teytms2i"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It brings me unbridled joy to look at, and &lt;a href="https://innerspiral.lol/Blog/comfort/comfort"&gt;that's great&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/sup&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="apple"></category><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="mac"></category><category term="macos"></category><category term="crt"></category><category term="diy"></category><category term="retrocomputing"></category><category term="marchintosh"></category></entry><entry><title>Summer videogame clears and mini-reviews</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/games-summer-2024.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-08-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2024-08-11:/games-summer-2024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;brat summer? more like yakuza bird character action summer&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's Summer! &lt;em&gt;I hate Summer!&lt;/em&gt; But it's always good to get some hits off the videogame backlog.&lt;br&gt;
I played some other games like &lt;a href="https://kokoscript.itch.io/wordhopper"&gt;Wordhopper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://warrrkus.itch.io/chalicebound"&gt;Chalicebound&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRikL6vpeto"&gt;Cleopatra Fortune&lt;/a&gt; as well, but this post is long enough already and I don't have as much to say about those - Do check them out though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Yakuza 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to "old" Yakuza after Kiwami 2 actually changes gameplay so much, things become fresh again!&lt;br&gt;
The Okinawa map is also a treat to run through, and this is probably the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vl6HrS_zc4M"&gt;best fishing minigame&lt;/a&gt; in a Yakuza thus far.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="man" src="./images/games/yak3.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
People who say this game's combat is a bore have probably never played a fighting game before since the solution to enemies blocking is the same here - Just grab them. It's that easy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to finish playing through the series before my Game pass sub lapses at the end of the year, but it's hard to avoid franchise fatigue with those games so I haven't started 4 yet...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Psychonauts 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/psy2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This game has a fairly slow start, but I found it very enjoyable when it actually opens up and lets you explore around.&lt;br&gt;
Very solid setpieces all around, it's rare these days to get a 3D platformer I would consider "AAA" that isn't Mario&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Schafer's still fucking got it when it comes to writing too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope Double Fine doesn't get swallowed by the Microsoft behemoth and can keep making games like this. Speaking of...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Hi-Fi Rush&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't believe you would close a game studio to get your accounting books green right after they'd release this &lt;strong&gt;banger&lt;/strong&gt; of a game.&lt;br&gt;
This is a crazy good character action game for what was basically Tango Gameworks' first shot at it - Microsoft had their Bayonetta and they just..threw it away like that&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="accurate recreation of a microsoft executive meeting" src="./images/games/hifi.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The emphasis on the beat system makes the game stand out while not veering into full-on rhythm game territory -- Although I certainly did enjoy the occasional Space Channel 5-esque QTE battles.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd recommend pirating this game, the studio's dead anyway and Microsoft doesn't deserve your money.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's surprising how close the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYJg_CCkYq8"&gt;"streamer soundtrack"&lt;/a&gt; gets to the licensed music used for some of the bosses - It's a good move considering the license rights will probably expire in 8 or so years and the original tracks will have to be pulled out.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Burning Rangers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lesser-known Sonic Team Saturn game. I'd played this before but couldn't get past the final level -- Not anymore!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Please don't look at my terrible led band routing i'm begging you" src="./images/kallax_crt.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the arcade gameplay in this better than NiGHTS, but the game really stretches the Saturn to its limits and has insanely aggressive culling as a result - Essential chunks of geometry will disappear as soon as they're about to leave the camera frame and it can make navigation difficult!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting of the game is super cool and it's a shame Sega never did anything else with it -- I can't shake the feeling that Sonic Team watched &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memories_(1995_film)"&gt;Magnetic Rose&lt;/a&gt; and thought "&lt;em&gt;ayo what if we mixed it with Sentai?&lt;/em&gt;".  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game's soundtrack has the killer combo of Naofumi Hataya(Sonic CD) and Fumie Kumatani(&lt;sub&gt;all the best sonic adventure songs don't @ me&lt;/sub&gt;) like with NiGHTS and it's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1pSk2EVCxiQ&amp;amp;t=1346s"&gt;really cool!&lt;/a&gt; Kinda like NiGHTS' dynamic music, the boss themes have multiple phases depending on their health and they flow in a really neat way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should check out this ongoing &lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/burning-rangers-tribute.1048/"&gt;Unity remake fanproject&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;BLiNX - The Time Sweeper&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another notch on my target list of playing all the Sonic Team-adjacent video games.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was aware this game gets surprisingly punishing for what was xbox's own mascot platformer at the time, but holy &lt;strong&gt;fuck&lt;/strong&gt; was I not ready - BLiNX gets &lt;strong&gt;merciless&lt;/strong&gt; by the time you're at the end.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="not even close to one of the worst parts not sure why i screenshotted this" src="./images/games/blinx2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;"why yes I would like a strict time limit, resource and ammo management in my cartoon 3D platformer"&lt;/em&gt; - words spoken by the utterly deranged  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will say that all the difficulty does make the game engaging despite the bullshit - It's quite satisying when you finally manage to nail everything correctly in a level.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Massive protip if you get to the end&lt;/em&gt; -- The boss rush is poorly programmed, so you can just hit &lt;strong&gt;start-&amp;gt;retry&lt;/strong&gt; on any individual boss without redoing the entire rush. Thank u naoto bigisland ohshima and god bless  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ex-ST composers Mariko Nanba(Chaotix, Sonic 06's Kingdom Valley) and Hataya worked on this game's soundtrack, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxVpeE55y2g"&gt;and it shows.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Similarly to BR, the final boss theme has health-dependent phases, except unlike the 3 or so phases of a BR boss, this one has like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DF_7eSCR5lQ"&gt;11??&lt;/a&gt; it's insane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Perfect Dark Zero&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to play this because hell, it's an early 2000s cyberpunk Xbox shooter!&lt;br&gt;
Give me those &lt;em&gt;glossy textures&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;moody environments&lt;/em&gt;, look at this shit this is straight up Deus Ex Infinite War-HD-texture-pack-core:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="hell yes, hell fucking yes" src="./images/games/pdz.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The UI is sponsored by Samsung! The second level is in a fucking nightclub! The &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G-H0J-D7lOY"&gt;vibes are immaculate!&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it falls apart because the locales become boring, the level design kinda sucks, the gunplay is barebones and the stealth aspects barely work, on top of Rare's mission-based FPS design which i've never been a huge fan of.&lt;br&gt;
The Xbox Series' auto-HDR for 360 backwards compatible titles does make the game pretty though.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thirsty Suitors&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is just Scott Pilgrim but with more gay in it" is a pretty apt description of this game... but I wouldn't consider that a negative.&lt;br&gt;
The characters and story in this are more endearing than I was expecting, and it's short enough that I actually wouldn't have minded a bit more. Jala is a &lt;strong&gt;massive girlfailure&lt;/strong&gt; and it's really fun to roll along for the self-improvement ride.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="we have reached a point in time where eva references are boomer clapbait and i am the boomer" src="./images/games/thirst.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The RPG gameplay does the SMT thing a bit where hitting enemy weaknesses gives you press turn advantage, but the game is nowhere near difficult enough for this to really come into play&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish the skateboarding was expanded upon more - It's no Jet Set Radio but it couldve gotten pretty close with more, longer levels. As it is there's no real point to it except screwing around for an hour or so. Budget issues probably..  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xA2X8vba8qc"&gt;quite good&lt;/a&gt;, although &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/WGRuIIxCqOE?t=160"&gt;Diya's theme&lt;/a&gt; pretty much clears all the other songs imo.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tyler is literally trans girl Shadow the Hedgehog and I will not elaborate.&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A Short Hike&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just an isometric 3D version of &lt;a href="./games-spring.html"&gt;Lil' Gator Game&lt;/a&gt; I played recently - I can see why people would complain about "comfy" games flooding the market, but I had a nice bit of fun with that one still.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="sounds rad" src="./images/games/hike3.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Since you're a bird in this you can glide out of the box, and the main means of progression is stamina powerups that also allow you to multi-jump.&lt;br&gt;
Aerial mobility gets quite fun towards the end as a result and I got some NiGHTS vibes out of the ending, which is always nice. (I feel like I'm mentioning NiGHTS a lot this time around for some reason...)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like that the internal resolution is a setting, allowing you to go from N64 chunky ass jaggies™️ to smooth modern indie game lowpoly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;An Outcry&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping up with some &lt;code&gt;certified RPG Maker 2003 horrorkino&lt;/code&gt; -- This game doesn't go for any cheap tricks when it comes to scaring you, opting to rely on the atmosphere and (pretty damn good) writing instead.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gameplay toys a bit with genre conventions(which you might or might not expect considering this is RPG Maker), but there's nothing obtuse in getting most of the endings here; You should probably save often though.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Vienna citybelt screenshot from an outcry" src="./images/games/outo.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Vienna citybelt is a mostly optional spot in the game but contains a ton of storytelling I really recommend clicking through - The election poster is one of my favorites despite how simple it is.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is about a flock of magic birds in Austria which kills everyone who isn't bird enough - It's (very) obvious what the birds are a metaphor for, and despite the game being two years old it still feels very relevant to &lt;em&gt;current world events.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very recommended, even if you're not too attuned to LGBT/queer terms - The birds come for everyone anyway.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; And even Mario is fairly rare since he only gets a full 3D platformer once per gen..&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; I'm aware DMC-style games are never going to sell as well as a CoD, but I don't think you can keep surviving as a console manufacturer if all you want are AAA million-sellers.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; Also you don't really have any weaknesses on your own and can deflect most status ailments through QTEs smh&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; In this blogpost anyway. &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="game pass"></category><category term="yakuza"></category><category term="psychonauts 2"></category><category term="burning rangers"></category><category term="sonic team"></category><category term="blinx"></category><category term="perfect dark zero"></category><category term="thirsty suitors"></category><category term="an outcry"></category><category term="soundtracks"></category></entry><entry><title>Early Spring videogame grab bag</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/games-spring.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2024-05-01:/games-spring.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;featuring coolgator 2000 and the noise&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Workers%27_Day"&gt;International Workers' Day&lt;/a&gt;! What better time to uhh, look back at all the videogames I've been playing.&lt;br&gt;
Thinking of all the man-hours that went into making those is quite humbling.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually played too many games since &lt;a href="./games-july.html"&gt;the last time&lt;/a&gt; I wrote up mini-reviews like this... And I'm forgetting some that I don't really have much to write about.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mahou Tsukai no Yoru&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="you can't actually take screenshots past chapter 4 or so because that would RUIN the experience" src="./images/games/mahoyo.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I actually played through this back in December, but since the FGO crossover event is happening &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AFaSQ1fIPOo"&gt;right now&lt;/a&gt;, I'm thinking about Mahoyo again.&lt;br&gt;
It'd been &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; since I last read a visual novel and even more since reading a Type-Moon one.. FGO doesn't count, it's all first-person and really doesn't flow as well.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production values on this are wild and it's especially better now that the latest releases are actually voiced; I give it a big rec if you're into magic in modern&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; times and all that jazz.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a great entrypoint into Type-Moon as well, no previous knowledge required!&lt;br&gt;
The story takes a small dip at the beginning because of boring school life stuff Nasu can't help himself write, but it only goes up after that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Coffee Talk 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/coffee.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's more Coffee Talk; Basically picks up right after the first game with a new batch of character stories.&lt;br&gt;
Great stuff if you like &lt;em&gt;bartender-type&lt;/em&gt; games. Yeah that's what I'm gonna call those now and there aren't enough of 'em  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack is a lot of chill jams and I basically dropped all of it into my playlist, but I really like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jaqOgKrYihY"&gt;this track&lt;/a&gt; in particular.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Atomic Heart&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pacing of this game is &lt;strong&gt;thoroughly&lt;/strong&gt; fucked; The gunplay is nice and I had a lot of fun with it once you hit the overworld, but that's only after 5 hours..&lt;br&gt;
The initial prologue+tutorialized dungeon at the beginning is entirely too long and not very interesting, unfortunately.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/atom-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The visual design of the game is great, love me some soviet futurism -- There's a lot of heart put into stuff like the fake cartoons in the save rooms where the characters look like they could sell you a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dendy_(console)"&gt;Dendy&lt;/a&gt; or something similar.&lt;br&gt;
You can tell they kinda ran out of budget for the environmental detail though, a lot of optional parts of the game end up looking samey.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story is actually fairly engaging when you get into it; They're still making DLCs so I might get back into the game at some point.
The soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R1eyjhTmErw&amp;amp;t=998s"&gt;pretty dope&lt;/a&gt;, although I didn't like the Mick Gordon tracks as much as I was hoping.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="I CLAPPED WHEN I SAW THE BIOSHOCK REFERENCE" src="./images/games/atom-2.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Splatoon 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked Splat 1 at the local thrift store and thought I'd play it before the Wii U online servers went down for good&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="How tf did we even win that one" src="./images/games/splatoon.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I'd never gotten into Splatoon before despite the fact team arena FPSes are right in my strike zone; Really loved it! Turf war is an easy game mode to pick up and the game is designed so that playing the objective comes naturally even if you just want to frag nerds.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online was also still active despite the fact Splatoon 1 was massively outdated by that point -- maybe because it's the only game of the three that didn't require you to pay a subscription?&lt;br&gt;
Xbox Live and its copycats have had terrible consequences for the human race...     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also the only game that has the &lt;a href="https://splatoonwiki.org/wiki/The_SQUID_GIRL"&gt;Ika Musume&lt;/a&gt; collab clothes! man I miss ika musume  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Yakuza Kiwami 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a year-long break between playing 0/Kiwami 1 and this -- And I'm glad I did, because this game just feels like Kiwami 1 again with less content.&lt;br&gt;
It's still Yakuza so it's still fun, but I see why people would consider this to be one of the weakest entries.&lt;br&gt;
Most of the side content is ripped straight from Yakuza 6 too, so it's going to feel real weird when I get to that game..  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OG &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BHWsYeVts0k"&gt;Yakuza 2 soundtrack&lt;/a&gt; they use here is still pretty good though.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one karaoke song where Kiryu puts on sunglasses and plays out a 2000s Evanescence music clip in the nolan batcave though and that goes so fucking hard look at this shit&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/kiwami2.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pizza Tower's Noise update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="its the noise" src="./images/games/noise.jpg"&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eMYTSESIsu8"&gt;woag&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noise feels massively unwieldy to play at first compared to the italian pizza man due to no wallrun, but at some point it just clicks and you start absolutely &lt;strong&gt;wrecking&lt;/strong&gt; the game -- Kinda like how it feels when you play Pizza Tower for the first time to begin with!&lt;br&gt;
Great NG+, you know you're doing something right when I'm just 100%ing it again.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Lil' Gator Game&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cool" src="./images/games/gator.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A short Breath of the Wild pastiche with lowpoly animals. It plays great and doesn't overstay its welcome, I'd recommend giving it a try through Game Pass or similar.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shield surfing is way more fun in this game than it ever was in BOTW!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Miscellaneous others&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sonic Superstars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atrocious&lt;/strong&gt; bosses, level design itself is fine if a bit uninspired except for some standouts (&lt;em&gt;Cyber Station&lt;/em&gt;), Trip is pretty fun to play and I hope they bring her back in future 2D Sonic installments.  &lt;br&gt;
People &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-z84TNg_POw"&gt;shit on the soundtrack&lt;/a&gt; but I actually like it despite how &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vRcOI4DbbDE"&gt;schizophrenic&lt;/a&gt; it feels.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Super Mario Wonder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wonder effects were fun, but this isn't a 2D Mario I'd replay. The badges are sold as "&lt;em&gt;make your own difficulty&lt;/em&gt;" but the base game is already easier than previous NSMBs..&lt;br&gt;
The final super expert level is straight up bad design and I never thought I'd say this of a Mario game, Nintendo officially went &lt;strong&gt;too far&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fortune Street Wii&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been on an Itadaki-binge lately and unlocked all the maps/characters in this; The game actually has a lot of depth and I'm glad this version is localized at least so it's easy to play with friends!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also there's a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FBLjEDI3qWQ"&gt;modpack&lt;/a&gt; and they put facingworlds in it with custom 3D models and everything it's awesome  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Entropy : Zero 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hunkering for some Half-Life a few months back and since I don't want to buy a VR headset for Alyx, I just played this &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1583720/Entropy__Zero_2/"&gt;off Steam&lt;/a&gt;; Great modded campaign, hard to not recommend it considering its unbeatable low price of &lt;strong&gt;Free&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fatum Betula&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is currently included in the &lt;a href="https://itch.io/b/2321/palestinian-relief-bundle"&gt;Palestinian relief bundle&lt;/a&gt; on itch alongside a bunch of other stuff I've been wanting to play, but I got it on Switch a few months back for free with gold Nintendo coins.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1hZ2UvNjEwMzg1LzMyNDUwNjIucG5n/original/0otHaw.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I really liked the main mechanic of "whatever you water the birch with determines your ending", you end up spending the entire game finding more and more convoluted water-based substances to keep in your bottle.&lt;br&gt;
Aesthetics are on point too if PS1 is your thing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Well it takes place in the 80s but that's still urban fantasy it counts i swear&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; Sure you can still play it with Pretendo but let's be honest it's never going to be as active as on the official servers&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="game pass"></category><category term="mahoyo"></category><category term="splatoon"></category><category term="atomic heart"></category><category term="pizza tower"></category><category term="yakuza"></category><category term="soundtracks"></category></entry><entry><title>SAGE videogame grab bag</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/sage-roundup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-10-01:/sage-roundup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;local man compiles all his reviews into one megapost&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sagexpo.org/index.html"&gt;SAGE 2023&lt;/a&gt; has ended, and I did good on my previous &lt;a href="./mcorigins-plus"&gt;promise&lt;/a&gt; by playing a &lt;strong&gt;heckuva lot&lt;/strong&gt; of games.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some notable ones I've played, in case you might be interested!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/gatoslip-chapter-0.1703/"&gt;Gatoslip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/gato.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I liked this a lot, topdown RPGs on megadrive always make me think about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crusader_of_Centy"&gt;Soleil/Centy&lt;/a&gt;, although the Deltarune inspirations are much more obvious -- Having sonicy platformer sequences instead of shmup is really fun.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/b-u-d-d-sage-23-demo.1740/"&gt;B.U.D.D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/budd.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This game truly wears its influences on its sleeve and reminds me I should finish that playthrough of Popful Mail&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I started all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat system is fun without being too overbearing as things stand, I think it'll be in a pretty good spot once the few missing moves are in the full game.&lt;br&gt;
The SA2-inspired combo meter made me smile but I usually don't get more than a 5 or 6x combo outside of the training room 🥲&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really great pixel art too! Look at this &lt;em&gt;blessed fake email client.&lt;/em&gt; 🙏 The image loading effect is simple but effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/susan-taxpayer-orientation-build.1887/"&gt;Susan Taxpayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/susan.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; dig the theming of this, 90's americana office settings are becoming a lost artform and I love how the soundtrack/SFX plays along. (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVLAPYx0dc8"&gt;tada.wav&lt;/a&gt; playing when you get every golden paperclip is chefs kiss tier shit)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="./games-february"&gt;Pizza Tower&lt;/a&gt; comparisons are inevitable considering the artstyle and the WL4 inspiration, but this game is much closer to Wario Land speedwise.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input windows are a bit tight for some moves right now and the demo doesn't show all the planned powerups, so I'm interested to see what comes next.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/sondro-gomez-sage-23.1676/"&gt;Sondro Gomez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/gomez.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Art direction is A+, both with the ingame sprites and the cutscenes/outside art.&lt;br&gt;
This has 3 playable characters, each going through variants of the same levels with (heavily) tweaked music&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;/level design.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite looking like Castlevania it's nowhere near as stiff, the game ends up reminding me more of Ducktales due to the variety of moves available.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/sonic-usb-online.1771/"&gt;Sonic USB Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/usb.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Sonic CD design philosophy cranked up to the absolute maximum, how the hell does this have so much content packed in I'm never getting through all of this &lt;em&gt;WHY IS ECCO GETTING IN THE SPECIAL STAGE RING&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the emphasis on badnik bounce combos to get extra XP, even though I'm not sure what the XP actually does...
Game is all &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_sv2g0eOzW0"&gt;vibes&lt;/a&gt; though, I really dig the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sk-yGZu_Yy4"&gt;soundtrack&lt;/a&gt; and aesthetics overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(the online features are ok? I guess? it's mostly people trying to figure out how to unlock characters)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/gunburst.1894/"&gt;Gunburst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/gunburst.jpeg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Small 1-boss demo, played it on a real MegaDrive for kicks.&lt;br&gt;
Game looks great! I could &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; beat that boss.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bounce attacks are way too unpredictable for a game with 1-hit kills.. I hope this gets completed though!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/sonic-and-the-gunslinger.1629/"&gt;Sonic and the Gunslinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="absolutely not a saturn game i swear" src="./images/games/sage/gunslinger.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4wzSw2iuk_8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023 YEAR OF FANG THE SNIPER YEAAAAAAAAAAAH&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't played &lt;a href="https://www.srb2.org/"&gt;SRB2&lt;/a&gt; in close to 20 years at this point and it's crazy to see the kind of stuff that can be built with it now...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the attempt at making this feel like a storybook game with multiple characters, it worked really well imo.
Levels are fun&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to go through, and I appreciate the attempt at giving each sonic level its own small gimmick to keep things fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/bun-n-gun-23-demo.1734/"&gt;Bun 'N Gun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bun" src="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/attachments/screenshots3-png.22754/"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Large levels to speed in while scavenger hunting for objectives.&lt;br&gt;
It's incredibly fun to just zip around the physics-based playground knowing the grappling hook can always save you even if you dash straight into a pit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective-based gameplay? Not as good sadly, targets are too small and having to capture them is a bore -- I think making them a bit larger and just having the player shoot them would help a lot in keeping the pace going.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/project-32x.1785/"&gt;Project 32X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/games/sage/32x.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An attempt at remaking &lt;a href="http://info.sonicretro.org/Sonic_Mars"&gt;Sonic Mars.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I appreciate the attempt in trying to make it look like a 32x game with the reduced draw distance and all, instead of reproducing chris' &lt;a href="http://info.sonicretro.org/File%3ASxc_sonicdemo1.gif"&gt;mockup&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://info.sonicretro.org/File%3ASxc_sonicdemo2.gif"&gt;movies&lt;/a&gt; 1:1.&lt;br&gt;
Not much going on for the moment, but might be cool if it gets finished.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/swolemochao-1-2-gym-of-the-year-edition.1660"&gt;Swolemochao 1&amp;amp;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="art is nice tho" src="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/attachments/07-04-at-14-00-13-uxir22tinc-png.21839/"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
i have a mechanical keyboard and the constant clacking while playing this made my wife leave me&lt;br&gt;
9/10  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/game-cycle.1649"&gt;Game Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="I'm aware I'm being pedantic but wow the pixel scaling on this is super off" src="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/attachments/newscreen1-png.21757/"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This has a fake operating system, so of course i'm checking it out! This is a selection of faux-shareware games to play.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the concept of playtesting/having different challenges for each game - It reminds me of the Game Center CX NDS games&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which had similar mini-challenges to keep you playing those faux-retro games.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Except the games here are not very engaging...&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I feel like there should be at least a few standout titles, while I can totally understand throwing a few intentional simple games for that authentic &lt;em&gt;90s shareware CD compilation&lt;/em&gt; experience, none of the three games in the demo really made me want to keep playing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; And actually try Monster World, watch Dirty Pair, etc etc you get the gist&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; The music theme got a bit boring hearing 3 variants of it in a row... I don't think this would be a problem in the final version where you'd play other levels before coming back to level 1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; except those water wheel jumps, incredibly painful even with the bubble shield :') &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Which are getting a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gBbEI8Pzan0"&gt;rerelease compilation&lt;/a&gt; on Switch with updated 3D graphics and &lt;strong&gt;new games&lt;/strong&gt;??? I don't think this'll get an english release sadly &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="gamedev"></category><category term="sage"></category><category term="sonic"></category><category term="fangames"></category><category term="demo"></category><category term="faux-OS"></category></entry><entry><title>Quake 2 RTX comparison screenshots</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/quake-rtx.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-31T00:01:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:01:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-07-31:/quake-rtx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Design is law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-1-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-1-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-2-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-2-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-3-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-3-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-4-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-4-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-5-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-5-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-6-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-6-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-7-off.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Quake 2 RTX screenshot" src="images/games/q2-7-on.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="quake"></category><category term="rtx"></category><category term="quake 2"></category></entry><entry><title>March-July videogame grab bag</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/games-july.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-07-31:/games-july.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;you could say I haven't &lt;em&gt;cranked&lt;/em&gt; one of those out in a while.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;...wow I totally meant to make more than &lt;a href="./games-february.html"&gt;one of those&lt;/a&gt; in the last 5 months but didn't get to it&lt;br&gt;
I'm writing this mostly because I want to use vscode's new &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_80#_markdown-format-pasted-urls-as-markdown-links"&gt;paste-as-markdown feature&lt;/a&gt;, which makes writing those blogposts a cinch!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of links, I've had the honor of Pixel &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pigadev/status/1685636317982650369?s=20"&gt;linking to DoujinSoft&lt;/a&gt; recently to showcase his old 2010 WarioWare DIY game&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. As a cranky old nerd who played Cave Story back in its freeware days, it's great to see those small games keep living through the internet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And speaking of small games and cranks..... &lt;sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;damn, double transition? showoff&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Panic Playdate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Recommendation Dog, for the Panic Playdate" src="images/games/playdate-1.gif"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 4 representing -- I've finally received my &lt;a href="https://play.date/"&gt;Playdate&lt;/a&gt; console in the mail recently.&lt;br&gt;
It &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; a lovely device, as expected buttons are nice, you can crank the crank and all that -- But what I've been liking most has to be the &lt;strong&gt;interface&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's all 1-bit dither&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; patterns like you're playing &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://hypercard.org/"&gt;Hypercard&lt;/a&gt;: The Console&lt;/em&gt;, but at a much smoother frame rate, and what the UI lacks in color, it more than makes up for in animation and style:&lt;br&gt;
🎁 New games show up in little present boxes like the 3DS/Wii U menus... Except the wrapping paper is customized for each game!&lt;br&gt;
🧶 The Settings menu has a breadcrumb navigation indicator, which each submenu having its own little icon when it shows up in the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the games, I'm still waiting to get all my season 1 stuff, but I've had a lot of fun with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.date/games/casual-birder/"&gt;Casual Birder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.date/games/crankin/"&gt;Crankin's Adventure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a game that could probably only exist on this device due to the fine analog control it requires...But the game itself hasn't grabbed me as much, it gets a bit too grindy and frustrating the further down the levels you go.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Reel Steal, a game from the Playdate Catalog you can doodle in" src="images/games/playdate-2.gif"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are some nice free games in the &lt;a href="https://play.date/games/"&gt;Catalog/Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as well now -- &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.date/games/recommendation-dog/"&gt;Recommendation Dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.date/games/reel-steal/"&gt;Reel Steal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are nice arcadey romps you should try.&lt;br&gt;
In another &lt;em&gt;probably-inspired-by-Nintendo-handhelds&lt;/em&gt; moment, the Store has its own &lt;a href="https://play.date/catalog/music"&gt;music.&lt;/a&gt; It's great&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Endless Monday: Dreams and Deadlines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice visual novel on Steam you should &lt;a href="https://endlessmonday.com/monthly/"&gt;consider buying&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
6 hours of reading, peppered with nice sub-games here and there, great pixel art, soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://chancethrash.bandcamp.com/track/cubical-for-two"&gt;good vibes&lt;/a&gt;. 👍  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm more biased than usual on this one considering I've been following the creator &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hcnone"&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a while, and you can totally see parallels between their real-life situation and the various plots in the game. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="look at this delightful pixelart corporate memphis... truly peak susan karecore" src="images/games/monday.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It's also a very...current-feeling story at times? There's nothing super deep as things mostly remain comedic, but the game digs a bit into the consequences of AI&lt;sup id="ref-5"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-5"&gt;##&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for current workforces, and how capital will drain you of resources and eventually come for your head if you let it run unchecked.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="diablo 4 in a nutshell" src="images/games/monday-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I've talked previously about &lt;a href="./2022-recap.html"&gt;"art that is unabashedly sincere"&lt;/a&gt;, and I feel that game matches this -- It's very much something that could only be made in 2023 with those gnawing doubts about the future of artists in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Quake 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full-on downgrade compared to Quake 1 holy hell&lt;br&gt;
Environments are worse, enemy design is boring, weapons are serviceable but that's it, and you can't break it in half by rocket/grenade launching 0/10&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="rtx tim willits is not real he cannot hurt you" src="images/games/q2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I played the RTX port by toggling between the OpenGL and RTX renderers to see the differences.&lt;br&gt;
You could argue the RTX version breaks the mood of the game but it's not like it has much to begin with..&lt;br&gt;
Here are &lt;a href="./quake-rtx.html"&gt;some RTX off/on comparisons&lt;/a&gt; if you're interested.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite has to be the nvidia logo slap-dashed in that one area you can rocketjump over to find a secret:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="nooo not the overpriced graphics card empire" src="images/games/q2-3-on.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I like the attempt at making interconnected maps with objectives that require you to move back and forth, but it's not really exploited all that well until the final level, which feels a bit more like an actual dungeon.&lt;br&gt;
Oh and the fucking &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YBQqDZwSUrA"&gt;skewered dopefish&lt;/a&gt; easter egg which you can only find by backtracking?? This game has the cringiest easter eggs in all of id software history and I mean it    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soundtrack is of course a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jY6yBTYxLko"&gt;banger&lt;/a&gt; everyone knows it, but I'm gonna have to go apologize to tim epic because Unreal was better than this mess&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;HROT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh lookie here, it's the better Quake 2!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="hit me with that slavsthetic NOW" src="images/games/hrot.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Despite having an even blander palette (&lt;em&gt;it's all brown&lt;/em&gt;), this game manages to have quite the variety of environments, accompanied by rock-solid level design.&lt;br&gt;
There's quite the variety of enemies and bosses too! And the super shotgun is A+, as shrimple as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the advertised theme being "post-USSR horror freakshow gone wrong", the game actually gets &lt;em&gt;goofier&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-6"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-6"&gt;###&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as the levels move on and you don't really get any kind of resolution out of the scraps of worldbuilding you're given...&lt;br&gt;
It's still a good time though!    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Slayers X: Terminal Aftermath: Vengance of the Slayer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capping off with another FPS, spinoff of the excellent &lt;em&gt;Hypnospace Outlaw&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="this image weighs...420 kilobytes. woah......." src="images/games/slayers-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now, it doesn't have as much fake operating system-ness as &lt;em&gt;Outlaw&lt;/em&gt;, but it delivers in spades in being a magnificent shitpost homage to early 2000's culture.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game...looks bad, but only when it &lt;em&gt;wants to&lt;/em&gt; -- There's real design and care here, and it walks that tightrope all the way to the end.&lt;br&gt;
There's something to be said about kamehameha-ing (literal)shit monsters with your sick &lt;code&gt;hacker powers&lt;/code&gt;, watching a cutscene with uncanny valley 3D rendering, then right afterwards finding a secret where the (fictional) single dad level designer put drawings by his three-year old in the map.     &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="there's still &amp;quot;some&amp;quot; fake computer stuff tho look how sick this is" src="images/games/slayers-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I really recommend this one, it's even on Game Pass right now if that's your thing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soundtrack is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZGo-MLA6YfU"&gt;triple A fucking incredible&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;s&gt;Jay Tholen&lt;/s&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIG Z. CORP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; has done it again!&lt;br&gt;
It's also a &lt;strong&gt;dynamic&lt;/strong&gt; soundtrack with combat/stress/relaxed layers for some reason? I approve, even though the in-game mixing is sometimes a bit jank-&lt;span style="font-family:comic sans ms; font-size: 25px"/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE S-BLADE HAS A HACKBLOOD CHARGE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Thankfully sakurai didn't do the same when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Sora_Sakurai/status/1589530503170109440?s=20"&gt;he reposted&lt;/a&gt; about his wwdiy game a few months ago, that'd have probably killed my bandwidth 🥲&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; The Gameboy Camera is a 2-bit photo device -- I should look into building the &lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2023/07/20/game-boy-style-camera-for-playdate/"&gt;Playdate Camera&lt;/a&gt; addon.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; I've thought the Playdate should have a Hudson &lt;a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/hudson-shooting-watch/"&gt;Shooting Watch&lt;/a&gt;-inspired app due to the color scheme, and browsing the Catalog, someone apparently &lt;a href="https://play.date/games/mash-gadget/"&gt;had the same idea.&lt;/a&gt; There's also a &lt;a href="https://play.date/games/stars-of-the-screen/"&gt;fake OS game&lt;/a&gt; oh my god &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; The web version of the song has occasional advertisement cutoffs like a real store -- Except they're selling you other Panic software like &lt;a href="https://nova.app/"&gt;Nova&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://panic.com/transmit/"&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt;. I can't hate it, but it is a bit distracting... &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-5"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-5"&gt;##&lt;/a&gt; I don't like saying AI as those machine learning algorithms are anything but intelligent, but that's what everyone is running with these days..&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-6"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-6"&gt;###&lt;/a&gt; There's a whole level about beating up giant newts as a reference to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_with_the_Newts"&gt;this old czech book.&lt;/a&gt; I should read it!&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="game pass"></category><category term="playdate"></category><category term="quake 2"></category><category term="hrot"></category><category term="SLAYERS X TERMINAL REVERGEANSE"></category><category term="endless monday"></category><category term="soundtracks"></category></entry><entry><title>January-February videogame grab bag</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/games-february.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-02-19:/games-february.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;if the pizza tower soundtrack doesn't end up pressed on pizza-colored vinyl records i will be sorely disappointed&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey, here's that vidya james post I wanted to write before going off on a tangent about &lt;a href="./game-manuals.html"&gt;manuals!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I had it kinda shelved, but the wacky woohoo pizza game got me wanting to write again, so let's get to it:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Paradise Killer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was on my "clear it through game pass" list forever, but I'm glad I got to it.&lt;br&gt;
You could resume it as "vaporwave danganronpa" as far as gameplay goes I guess?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Paradise Killer, in the civilian apartments at sunset" src="images/games/paradise-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It's very much a different experience though, just massive chill vibes for a good couple of hours while you comb the island over to piece together the local murder mystery&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It doesn't overstay its welcome, yet there's more than enough stuff to keep you entertained with minimal backtracking.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just...get the movement upgrades fast, and dial the voice clip frequency &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; down in the settings, lest you create your &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; murder mystery after hearing &lt;em&gt;"The investigator is here!"&lt;/em&gt; for the tenth time in a conversation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Another screenshot of Paradise Killer. oh to be lounging on the beach alongside the obsidian obelisks looking at the alien pyramid in the far distance" src="images/games/paradise-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The aesthetic is unparalleled in this and really contributes to the good vibes; This is one of those games I'd keep installed just to pop it in every now and then and walk around the environments.&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xfgbb0uXH4s"&gt;Also, the soundtrack is fantastic.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="NOSTALGIC SOUNDS. MEMORIES OF THE CAREFREE DAYS NOW LOST. even the music obtained screen goes so fucking hard on the vapor this should be illegal" src="images/games/paradise-3.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;SIGNALIS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played this one a few months back already, but thought I'd still talk a bit about it.&lt;br&gt;
Survival horror with impeccable art direction, good gameplay and a story that feels like David Lynch wrote it after reading a bunch of Lovecraft books.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;strong&gt;casuals&lt;/strong&gt; don't like the inventory management in this, but you can't really have a good horror game without the constant existential dread of not having enough space!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also there's a small fake operating system you can find near the end:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A screenshot of &amp;quot;Postbox 4.3&amp;quot; from SIGNALIS - I'd post more of it but I don't want to spoil the game too much" src="images/games/signalis-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We got that nice Windows 3.1 aesthetic with touches of 95, &lt;em&gt;good shit&lt;/em&gt;!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://signalis-ost.bandcamp.com/track/safe-room"&gt;Also, the soundtrack is fantastic.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Digital Exorcist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short Snatcher-inspired game on &lt;a href="https://coolbeansproductions.itch.io/digital-exorcist"&gt;itch.io.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Digital Exorcist where the protag talks about SanctuariOS, &amp;quot;the holiest operating system&amp;quot;" src="images/games/digital_exorcist.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;TERRY DAVIS LIVES&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked it a lot!&lt;br&gt;
Writing about demons crawling the internet tickles my Soul Hackers bone, so that always gets a thumbs up from me.&lt;br&gt;
It's only an hour or so, entirely worth the time -- wouldn't mind seeing more.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://djtakataka.bandcamp.com/track/battle-in-the-aethernet"&gt;Also, the soundtrack is pretty cool.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Unreal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;the game not the engine you dolts&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played Quake semi-recently through the remaster, I wanted to get back to Unreal and finally finish it!&lt;br&gt;
It was...kinda boring?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game looks stunning and really showcases the large environments you could do on UE1... yet most of the combat loop is oriented towards shoving you in cramped hallways with ninja aliens. I wasn't asking for Serious Sam tier open area fights, but it'd have been nice to get a bit more of a balance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="it do be looking good tho (screenshot from na pali haven kinoest map in the game)" src="images/games/unreal-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also some of the game design is fucking weird in this, what's the deal with the locked rooms with endless respawning enemies making you kill like 50 of them to proceed? The game didn't need padding, it's already 10 hours long!&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I still think it was worth playing despite that, though. fuck you epic for delisting this   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9IISjIMpepo&amp;amp;t=9256s"&gt;Also, the soundtrack is fantastic.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can never have enough Alex Brandon/Michiel van den Bos! It follows a similar structure to the Deus Ex soundtrack with dynamic pieces depending on what the level does, which is certainly one thing I'll give it over Quake.&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pizza Tower&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it, the &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2231450/Pizza_Tower/"&gt;Wario Land where you go fast&lt;/a&gt;! I adore the artstyle of this game and can't imagine how many hours of work were poured into drawing all those unhinged italians. (Seriously, the amount of art assets in this 7h game? incredible)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="VERY...... A NICE!" src="images/games/pizza.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I've thought a few times before of a combo system where you could keep a combo from the beginning to the end of a stage without dropping it, but always wondered how you'd make it fit with non-score attack aspects like finding secrets.&lt;br&gt;
How do you make those fun to find for normal players, while weaving them into your score attack so that the secrets aren't a one-time fun thing you do for completionism? Pizza Tower just fucking does it, &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; nails it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending is teased throughout the entire game so it doesn't come as a surprise when it lands, but the execution is so good you'll still love the absolute crap out of it.&lt;br&gt;
fucking goty we didn't even make it to march, pack it up zelda you're done  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ronandecastel.bandcamp.com/track/pumpin-hot-stuff"&gt;Also, the soundtrack is &lt;strong&gt;beyond&lt;/strong&gt; fantastic.&lt;/a&gt; It's got all my favorite samples in it!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Which isn't very complex but then again I wanted to chill, not unwind a komaeda-tier madhouse murder with this one&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; except you can't do that with gamepass god damn it phil fine i'll buy the game&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; And they had to cut a ton of shit from the game that ended up in the expansion pack! &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; sorry trent i still love you, I certainly recommend the &lt;a href="https://signalis-ost.bandcamp.com/track/mynah"&gt;signalis soundtrack&lt;/a&gt; again if you want some of that NiNcore &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="game pass"></category><category term="unreal"></category><category term="pizza tower"></category><category term="signalis"></category><category term="paradise killer"></category><category term="digital exorcist"></category><category term="faux-OS"></category><category term="soundtracks"></category></entry><entry><title>Some thoughts on the Arc Browser</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/arc-thoughts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-01-08:/arc-thoughts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Isn't 'The Browser Company' kind of a pretentious name?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Remember when the Internet Explorer browser engine was the most ubiquitous thing because it was forcibly integrated into Windows and everyone could use it?&lt;br&gt;
Heck, you could even make &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; own web browser by just slapping some Win32 controls on top of a webview, look at this old Winforms app someone made eons ago and that I kept in my "old stuff" folder for some reason:    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="yeah the IE11 engine is starting to show its age tho" src="images/arc/cakebrowser.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the opportunity to try out &lt;a href="https://arc.net/"&gt;Arc&lt;/a&gt;, a new web browser setting to &lt;code&gt;"think as quickly as we do, take work off of our plates, and pull our creativity forward"&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;"let go of the old internet"&lt;/code&gt;, yknow, tech startup stuff.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their brand/marketing is pretty good&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and since the browser was shrouded in secrecy for a while I got interested...&lt;br&gt;
Like all tech startup stuff, the beta is an invite-only cool club thing because we can't just have &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; try our software I guess ¯\_(ツ)_/¯ &lt;br&gt;
At least they &lt;strong&gt;actually&lt;/strong&gt; give you a member card here so I can't really complain too much, look how pretty it is!    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/arc/cool_club.jpg" width="400"/&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Interface and Browser organization&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arc browser is a UI wrapper around Chromium like most new browsers these days, but unlike Vivaldi I quite like the interface here! It's Mac-only for now and is actually using native UI components, which helps a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of micro-interaction animations and other niceties peppered throughout the interface -- 
Since I'm more of a Windows user, I can only hope they manage to do the same &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/4/23438365/the-arc-browser-is-coming-to-windows"&gt;there.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main idea behind Arc is to reduce on your browser clutter by automatically Marie Kondo-ing your tabs away after a few days, unless you specifically move them &lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; the New Tab button, where they'll never close.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/arc/arc_1.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For "webapps" that you always keep open, you can also drag a tab all the way up, where it'll transform into a big fat toggle button. I personally prefer extracting webapps away from the browser when possible&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so I can use the OS to multitask instead, because it'll usually be miles ahead of what a single app can do 😤  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the area below New Tab be this ephemeral space allows for some interesting UI choices, like putting downloads alongside your tabs. I can appreciate the experiment, but as a dedicated Tab Hoarder™️ I'd probably end up pinning everything...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as Tab organization itself goes, you've got folders, which give you one level of hierarchy only(meh). But if you want one more level, you can use &lt;strong&gt;Spaces&lt;/strong&gt;, which I consider to be a very cool spin on web browsing compartmentalization.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/arc/arc_3.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaces end up at the bottom of the sidebar with the icon/emoji you give them, and each space has its own set of tabs and folders. If you want, you can give a space a different &lt;strong&gt;profile&lt;/strong&gt;, which is basically a separate cookie/data storage like what Firefox Containers do.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite powerful for Home/Work separation and other stuff like per-project tab bundles - But once you're on a space proper you'll still notice that the tab interface can't really hold a lot of tabs (even with folders), which is very much a deliberate choice by the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Split View&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Y'know how browsers all mostly embraced the "sidebar/side view" thing these days, either for extensions or additional lightweight multitasking? Arc just goes whole hog on the concept with a Split View feature that allows you to have up to 4 tabs side-by-side.&lt;br&gt;
The tabs merge in a single line on the sidebar, which is a nice touch.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Arc, showing four doujinsoft tabs side by side playing different games. this is quite silly" src="images/arc/arc_4.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;Playing DIY games on &lt;a href="http://diy.tvc-16.science"&gt;DoujinSoft&lt;/a&gt; certainly gets more challenging when you have to play four of them simultaneously...&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the interface of Arc is overall very spacious, for some reason the multitasking menu is this small set of three dots on the right side of each tab - What is this, the iPad?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="extension/multitasking menu on arc, with the tsukihi extension opened in a small adjacent window" src="images/arc/arc_extension.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The multitasking menu is also where extensions live, and opening an extension shows it up in a little floating window -- Which is something I thought was &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; cool at first, because sometimes I do want my extension to stick around on screen while I'm doing browser stuff instead of being a quick overlay like all other browsers do.&lt;br&gt;
Except that the window autocloses as soon as you click outside it, so it's basically just an overlay anyways. 😩😩  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Other features&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each space can have a dedicated &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a set of up to three accent colors you can choose. Although you can only really choose the primary colors, as the browser will "derive" the others for you so that the interface remains nice.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;no hot dog stand...&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser comes with uBlock Origin pre-installed as an adblocker, and comes with a "Boost" feature that's basically Stylish+Greasemonkey, allowing you to give any website custom CSS/JS. It's pretty good! The split view also makes working on custom styles and scripts a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't take a screenshot of it (ha), but the &lt;strong&gt;screenshot&lt;/strong&gt; tool can always be quickly reached from the address bar, and it is &lt;em&gt;surprisingly&lt;/em&gt; powerful -- You can select DOM regions like other browsers, but there's also some basic editing tools on top of it.&lt;br&gt;
It ties into the "Easel" feature, which is some kind of collaborative whiteboard thing? This isn't really the kind of thing I'd do in a web browser, but it's there if you want it&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="images/arc/arc_easel.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks good and it tries to be your Internet swiss army knife... I appreciate some of the choices, but I'd probably end up only using a third of what Arc offers.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaces are a really nice feature and I'd like to use those instead of juggling two Firefox windows like I do, but the tab management side of things is a bit too limiting for me I'd say? Firefox + &lt;a href="https://github.com/piroor/treestyletab"&gt;Tree Style Tabs&lt;/a&gt; remains undefeated!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an &lt;a href="https://arc.net/gift/ac63e7b"&gt;invite code&lt;/a&gt; for the Arc cool club in case you want to try it out.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;I am a sucker for serifs/renaissance art mixed with corporate aesthetics I guess&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; Swift bindings to WinUI? they sure aren't making their lives easy on that one that's commendable&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; Using PWAs, third party clients or &lt;em&gt;shudders&lt;/em&gt; awful electron wrappers... &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; One nice feature of easels is that you can make your screenshots "live", which basically turns them into small webviews. This won't work everywhere, but it's nice for dashboard stuff! &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="macos"></category><category term="apple"></category><category term="internet browsers"></category><category term="startup stuff"></category></entry><entry><title>The 2022 Recap</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/2022-recap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-12-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2022-12-30:/2022-recap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's the most wonderful time of the year!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been mostly winding down playing &lt;a href="https://kolektiva.social/@Difegue/109503827535767577"&gt;Sonic games&lt;/a&gt;, catching up on seasonal anime and trying to get through this box of Finnish sweets I received as part of a secret santa. (I have no idea how they eat &lt;a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salmiakki"&gt;this stuff&lt;/a&gt;, it is an absolute ordeal)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as social media goes, I've been enjoying reading my timeline on the &lt;a href="https://kolektiva.social/@Difegue"&gt;funny elephant website&lt;/a&gt; much more than Twitter recently, but it's quite hard to drop the blue bird entirely considering I follow a bunch of artists on it...&lt;br&gt;
Mastodon is too tech-oriented to catch on with art twitter imo, maybe &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/photomatt/status/1594577983028740096"&gt;Tumblr implementing ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt; will be the savior? Still feels quite unlikely.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022 was a thoroughly packed year for me on pretty much all levels, so when looking back for this end-of-year blogpost I kinda wonder how the fuck I made all this stuff -- Let's aim to be a better &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cassiecodes/status/1592974814352146432"&gt;⅒&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; rockstar dev&lt;/a&gt; in the coming year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;LANraragi&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've put out 4 (and a half) LRR releases this year for a total of &lt;code&gt;+7838/-3539&lt;/code&gt; LoC, ending at &lt;a href="https://github.com/Difegue/LANraragi/releases/tag/v.0.8.8"&gt;0.8.8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
This year was mostly performance improvements on the thumbnail and search front -- I feel the codebase is in a pretty good shape atm, so maybe we'll land some nice features for 0.9.0 in 2023 if we get there.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Difegue/LANraragi/issues/519"&gt;Meta-archives/tankobon&lt;/a&gt; support is a big one, but I'd also like to finally work on a better onboarding UI and an external plugin repository. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added &lt;a href="https://github.com/Difegue/LANraragi/issues/665"&gt;JPEGXL support&lt;/a&gt; right before Google killed it by &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/jpegxl/comments/zhbiy1/jpegxl_removed_from_chromium_source/"&gt;removing it from Chromium&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="smh google i swear to god" src="images/coolmeme.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;DoujinSoft&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was planning to do...absolutely nothing with DoujinSoft this year?&lt;br&gt;
But of course &lt;a href="./doujinsoft-3.html"&gt;life found a way&lt;/a&gt; and we got &lt;a href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/10503-website-allows-you-to-play-fan-made-warioware-d-i-y-microgames-in-your-browser"&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; on GoNintendo. What the fuck man&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Post this cat when they'll least expect it" src="images/doujinsoft/necoarc.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We broke the &lt;code&gt;105 000&lt;/code&gt; games uploaded mark this year I believe, and well, I'm still approving new DIY content and receiving weird shit via Wii Mail on a weekly basis. I also &lt;a href="https://gamingreinvented.com/interview/lets-interview-doujinsoft-creator-difegue/"&gt;got interviewed!&lt;/a&gt; That was kinda fun.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to eventually add missing features to the webplayer to make it a bit more like real WarioWare and allow users to share their own game mixes, but in the meantime, why not try out this &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/collection?id=z_dfugselects"&gt;custom playlist&lt;/a&gt; I put together?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;SAGE 2022 and Sonic McOrigins&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has been the best for Sonic in...quite a long time!&lt;br&gt;
I'm happy to have contributed to it in a small way by putting together that &lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/sonic-mcorigins.1352/"&gt;LCD simulator archive&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a lot of nice comments from people about how those games were parts of their childhood they'd forgotten about; One of the major reasons for building this was to make sure this stuff would be remembered (as cheap as the games are), so it's great to see others share that sentiment&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="The cursed missing three games..." src="images/lcdonald/missing_three.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I do have the missing three games now, so you can probably expect a &lt;em&gt;McOrigins DX &amp;amp; Knuckles&lt;/em&gt; for SAGE 2023&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAGE is always chock full of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BrockCrocodile/status/1569030514224365573"&gt;incredible stuff&lt;/a&gt;, so I was quite humbled to still receive some &lt;a href="https://segabits.com/blog/2022/09/04/playable-at-sage-2022-sonic-mcorigins-featuring-the-mcd-lcd-sonic-toys/"&gt;coverage&lt;/a&gt; in the midst of all the heavy-hitters. It made for pretty good Twitch content as well, but most of the VODs for those are gone now. 😔  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Sonic stuff, there's a recording of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_-BDnNia11s"&gt;Re: Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt; Sega CD pixel art/music album on YouTube now -- I recommend giving it a look/listen, it's &lt;code&gt;cool&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Stylophone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="./stylophone-25.html"&gt;Stylophone 2.5&lt;/a&gt; was mostly just polishing off and releasing work from 2021 because I hate letting work go to waste; Financially speaking it wasn't a particularly smart move considering the 100€ apple tax&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I almost made back half of it, ain't that neat?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="images/stylophone/v25-ipad.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I might release a 2.6 with some bugfixes and layout improvements (it's a bit messy on some iPhones...), but I don't think I'll pay the 100€ again next year?   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the EU directives will likely force Apple to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-12-13/will-apple-allow-users-to-install-third-party-app-stores-sideload-in-europe"&gt;allow side-loading in the next year&lt;/a&gt;, it'd certainly be nice if that yearly tax went away/was reduced as well; Probably just wishful thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;DialogueForest and Gamedev&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot of DialogueForest, editing some text" src="images/dialogueforest.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Keen followers might know I've been dabbling in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Difegue/status/1476936024752365569?s=20"&gt;some gamedev&lt;/a&gt; for a little while now.&lt;br&gt;
The basic pitch for the game is "&lt;code&gt;Digital: A Love Story/Hypnospace Outlaw but in 1989/NeXtSTEP aesthetics&lt;/code&gt;", so there's quite a bit of reading on BBSes and emails to do -- And consequently, quite a bit of dialogue for me to write...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DialogueForest&lt;/em&gt; is an UWP/WinUI 2.6 app I cooked at the beginning of the year to make writing those longer form mail/BBS dialogue pieces easier to organize and link to each other. It works pretty well! And I barely used it. 😤&lt;br&gt;
The app has some rough edges, but I should finish it up and make it a free download on itch.io or something.&lt;br&gt;
Adding a daily wordcount/notification system is one of the missing bits, and it would probably make me use the thing more too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't make much game progress this year, which makes sense considering basically &lt;em&gt;everything else&lt;/em&gt; took time instead; I also probably underestimated the workload of writing quite a bit! &lt;strong&gt;It's hard!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Nevertheless, here's some footage of the faux-OS and the application system:   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width="800" autoplay="true" loop="true" src="images/gamedev/animationsucc.webm"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Misc 2023 thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been looking at a bunch of &lt;a href="https://cinni.net/"&gt;small&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://maya.land/"&gt;personal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://tilde.town/"&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://sadgrl.online/"&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt; - kinda like what this blog is!&lt;br&gt;
While Mastodon is fun, I think there's a lot of value in keeping your own little corner of the Internet for people to look at.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heck, you don't even need to know HTML like in the geocities days now, it's all &lt;a href="https://mmm.page/"&gt;wysiwyg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and shit!&lt;br&gt;
I'd like to use this blog more in the upcoming year to just write about whatever - I don't have a fancy newsletter&lt;sup id="ref-5"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-5"&gt;##&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; button or anything but ol' reliable &lt;a href="https://tvc-16.science/feeds/all.atom.xml"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; is still a thing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does feel like the winds of the Internet are shifting a bit in 2023(here's a &lt;a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/lab/new-avenues/"&gt;nice read&lt;/a&gt;), so keeping the effortposting to the TVC-16 helps in case everyone moves to yet another platform&lt;sup id="ref-6"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-6"&gt;###&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
All the blue bird will get from me is shitposting and external links.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="lmao" src="images/memupatcher/lmao.gif"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 'bout that dreaded year of 2023, what's in the cards? uhhh I dunno quick shit out some links   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've been looking at &lt;a href="https://blog.holopin.io/posts/holobytes-and-holopals"&gt;Holopin&lt;/a&gt; since last Hacktoberfest - I find the concept amusing and hope they'll accept my application for the OSS plan so I can make virtual badges out of all the Spline 3D stuff I made this year. 😌  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows 11 Widgets are opening up to &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/apps/develop/widgets/implement-widget-provider-win32"&gt;third-party&lt;/a&gt; app developers: That's a pretty good incentive for me to dig RSS Live Tiles from its grave!  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transitions made by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kamikazenosyain/status/1604159235507437568"&gt;Kamikaze Douga&lt;/a&gt; for Pop Team Epic S2 are awesome and would make for a nice screensaver ala &lt;a href="https://github.com/pedrommcarrasco/Brooklyn"&gt;Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obsidian has a cool new &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/canvas"&gt;graph view&lt;/a&gt; now - Sometimes I feel like I should give it a shot..  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On more generic terms, I read a post recently about "&lt;code&gt;art that is unabashedly sincere/only you can make&lt;/code&gt;", and that's something I wish I was doing more - You could argue that some of the projects here are already very much personal expression/stuff that nobody else would make, but ehhhh I wouldn't really consider it art yknow?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's something awesome about being able to put a bit of yourself out there like that - Maybe I can do some more of that in the gamedev stuff.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading this far! (or skipping to the end)&lt;br&gt;
I don't do longer-form writing like this too often so I've been looking at the draft in the Firefox Reader View to make sure the estimated reading time doesn't go beyond 9 minutes. 😤 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Most of the other comments were memes about the pakistani commercials, of course.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; There are some scans I should upload to Sonic Retro as well...&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; The dev certificate also allowed me to sign/notarize the macOS version of Sonic McOrigins, which is cool I guess&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/KCvW-2mZBlU?t=28"&gt;Just a guy who loves adventure!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-5"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-5"&gt;##&lt;/a&gt; I've been enjoying the resurgence of email newsletters as well - While Revue has already been murdered, thank god for Substack! Hope it stays.&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-6"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-6"&gt;###&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/robinsloan/spring-83"&gt;Spring '83&lt;/a&gt; isn't really a platform per se, but I like the concept/thought experiment behind it. It kinda feels like everyone would have his lil' widget/card and you could just smash 'em all in one big page...&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blogposting"></category><category term="lanraragi"></category><category term="stylophone"></category><category term="doujinsoft"></category><category term="uwp"></category><category term="sonic"></category><category term="mcdonalds"></category><category term="gamedev"></category></entry></feed>