<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Blogopolis - Gamedev</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://tvc-16.science/feeds/gamedev.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://tvc-16.science/</id><updated>2025-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Announcing Yonderu! DoujinSoft for the Playdate</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/yonderu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2025-07-21:/yonderu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;it's officially the summer of wario&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy "end of season 2" to all &lt;a href="https://play.date/"&gt;Playdate&lt;/a&gt; owners! Did you enjoy the games?&lt;br&gt;
I actually haven't played most of them yet... since as soon as I heard the SDK now officially had &lt;em&gt;networking support&lt;/em&gt;, I saw an opportunity to get some &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/difegue.tvc-16.science/post/3ljlqtygsek27"&gt;brainworms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; out of my skull.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, two months later, I'm proud to present my &lt;a href="/sonic-drift-mania.html"&gt;second ever&lt;/a&gt; Playdate release.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video autoplay loop src="./images/doujinsoft/yd_intro.mp4" muted=true title="Title screen for Yonderu! DoujinSoft"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yonderu! DoujinSoft&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;sub&gt;(approximately translates to "Let's read! DoujinSoft"&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/sub&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;comic reader&lt;/em&gt; for the Playdate which is directly hooked up to the &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/"&gt;DoujinSoft Store&lt;/a&gt;, the largest content archive for 2010's&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WarioWare_DIY"&gt; WarioWare DIY&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comics in WWDIY are black-and-white 193 x 126 x 4-strip images, which makes them a nearly perfect fit for the Playdate screen! Someone did &lt;a href="https://paulstraw.itch.io/xkpd"&gt;the same thing with XKCD&lt;/a&gt; comics, so you know this is a winner. 😎  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ala &lt;em&gt;Garfield-in-the-newspaper&lt;/em&gt;, the game will download a &lt;strong&gt;new comic&lt;/strong&gt; every day from a curated selection for users to read, share, and rate.&lt;br&gt;
And if you want more, you can also download all the latest comics uploaded to the store by the DIY community... which is still pretty active! Here's &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/comics?id=4c527559b4f1bf1bded41e00ec456fb3"&gt;a comic with a Deltarune ch3 joke&lt;/a&gt;, for example.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...And of course, you can use the crank to scroll between pages.
&lt;img alt="the tutorial turtle is undying" src="/images/doujinsoft/yd_scroll.gif"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You can download the game on itch with the link below.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://itch.io/embed/3705003" width="552" height="167" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;a href="https://difegue.itch.io/yonderu-doujinsoft"&gt;Yonderu! DoujinSoft by dfug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always felt that comics are kind of the black sheep of DIY's offerings - The microgames are obviously the main draw, and the music maker gets a fair amount of love from the same folks who like to make absurdly complex compositions in Mario Paint...&lt;br&gt;
There's some real funny stuff in the &lt;em&gt;40000+&lt;/em&gt; comics uploaded to the archive though, and I'm hoping this Playdate outing will help shine a bit more light on them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is actually the &lt;strong&gt;first time&lt;/strong&gt; you can submit &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/surveys"&gt;ratings&lt;/a&gt; for WWDIY content without using a Wii with DIY Showcase! It's pretty fun being able to stretch the lifetime of a game like this utterly beyond what it was designed to do.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A DSi and a Playdate both reading the tutorial comic -- i actually used mspaint's new remove background feature for the blur on this and was pleasantly surprised" src="images/doujinsoft/yonderu.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
While the Playdate is a great fit for this kind of pick-up-and-play &lt;sub&gt;(or is it pick-up-and-read?)&lt;/sub&gt; content, I did have to rework a few bits of the experience for it to work on Panic's 1-bit console;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comic iconography has mostly been redrawn, and I used some MacPaint patterns to replace the colors that comic creators can use for their covers in the original game. It gives quite a different vibe from the original! &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A comic cover in the OG NDS game, and how it looks in Yonderu." src="images/doujinsoft/yd_covers.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sound bites that play when you start/finish a comic have also been changed compared to the originals; I had fun digging through samples to make 10 new intro/outros, but that was at the point where I realized I might have spent way more time building this than I had anticipated...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That time included picking up the &lt;em&gt;actual DIY comic creator&lt;/em&gt; again to make an in-game tutorial too.&lt;br&gt;
The text tools on the original NDS are still painful, and my drawing skills haven't really evolved since 2014&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="images/doujinsoft/yd_tutorial.png" title="" style="width: 40%;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; This technically doesn't follow the original vision™️ of putting DIY comics on the Pebble watch, but now that I made all the server tooling for it? Maybe for the next Rebble hackathon.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; Real connaisseurs will of course understand this is a reference to the Japanese name for WarioWare DIY Showcase, &lt;i&gt;"Asobu! Made in Ore"&lt;/i&gt;... my naming sense is truly immaculate. Hire me Microsoft, i'll fix your dogshit names before you can even put me in your sixth round of layoffs &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; before you ask yes the comic reading guy is literally just a knockoff servbot&lt;/sup&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="nintendo"></category><category term="nintendo ds"></category><category term="warioware"></category><category term="doujinsoft"></category><category term="playdate"></category><category term="comics"></category><category term="gamedev"></category></entry><entry><title>Funtography is part of Indiepocalypse #65!</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/indiepocalypse.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2025-06-10:/indiepocalypse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patch notes: The Grape assistant has turned into a Medjed&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Woops, haven't written a blogpost in a few months..&lt;br&gt;
I've been busy playing video games&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/difegue.tvc-16.science/post/3lqo3v7c3cc2k"&gt;memeing something up with the Playdate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
But in the meantime, my &lt;a href="./funtography.html"&gt;silly gameboy camera VN&lt;/a&gt; has made it into Indiepocalypse Issue 65!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pizzapranks.com/"&gt;Indiepocalypse&lt;/a&gt; is a curated monthly collection looking to highlight the very best of the alternative indie game scene.&lt;br&gt;
Please &lt;a href="https://pizzapranks.itch.io/indiepocalypse-65"&gt;give it a look&lt;/a&gt;, it's not even the only game in there with an operating system interface!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've remade a build of Funtography that includes a few QoL changes from the (slowly) ongoing larger fake OS project, so if you haven't played it yet, dare I say... there's never been a better time??  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="I actually finally made a proper icon for the clock but it's not in this screenshot smh" src="./images/funtography/ft_indiepocalypse.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a few extra words about the game for the included zine, feel free to read them below if you want some more Funtolore™️:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey! I hope you're enjoying the zine.
People often wonder what the hell the fake OS has to do with Funtography as a game and the reality of it is.... nothing! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been building this fake OS with super shaky foundations in Unity 2019 for 5 years by now to try and make a 80's BBS simulator game ala Digital, and Funtography is "just" a full playable game that I've built within that framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of "VN adventure game with Gameboy Camera pictures" was stuck in my head for nearly 15 years, so at some point I just thought fuck it, let's do it in here! It was quite cathartic to actually get this out in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is pretty fun to look back at; It's silly and the ending is very rushed, but I enjoy writing alt-history stuff like this that grounds itself in real events and kinda just runs with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually still proud of the soundtrack for this - It's a hodgepodge of slowed-down chiptune horrors, but for someone who has negative music skills, I still think it's pretty good... 
I hope you'll be interested enough to read up to when "special stage" plays as the BGM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case the full fake OS game never comes out, at least this VN is something that actually shipped I can look back on. It's been hard to make time for gamedev recently, but I'm keeping at it! 
This dumb idea will probably kill me at some point if I don't actually get it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Indiepocalypse build has a few QOL updates from the old Itch version I've made since 2023, namely actualy functional UI scaling, a very dodgy scanline filter, and a 2X zoom option for the Camera view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you clear the game, you'll unlock the sound test in the CD Player program! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; I haven't made a mini-review post in a hot minute but I enjoyed the hell out of "Get in the Car, Loser!" after finally playing it a month ago. also yeah deltarune ch3/4 i guess &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="gamedev"></category><category term="unity"></category><category term="c#"></category><category term=".net"></category><category term="gameboy"></category><category term="gameboy camera"></category><category term="faux-OS"></category><category term="indiepocalypse"></category></entry><entry><title>Making new microgames in WarioWare DIY, 14 years later</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/diy-fi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2025-01-28:/diy-fi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;hahaha!!! i made a fake OS on the nintendo ds!!!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite running the largest &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/"&gt;WarioWare DIY archive&lt;/a&gt; for about eight years now&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I hadn't made any games with it since... &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=66ff7257b3d7ea3361c3745ed36ed05e"&gt;wow, 2011!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
DIY is of course very limiting as a game creation tool, but I'm quite grateful to it for being the one of the ways I released "proper" games online, after multiple attempts with Game Maker 7/8 in the late 2000s&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While running those old GM games on modern hardware is a pain, the various efforts around DIY have made it surpisingly easy to pick up and use even nowadays. &lt;sub&gt;(I don't think you'd be getting &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=2d92ffcc9d1ec20a024d37210a35f51d"&gt;skibidi games&lt;/a&gt; otherwise..)&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There's the &lt;a href="./doujinsoft-3.html"&gt;built-in&lt;/a&gt; players on DoujinSoft, of course, but also working online with &lt;a href="https://www.wiilink24.com/"&gt;WiiLink&lt;/a&gt; and Wimmfi for the original games.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..And the new kid on the block, &lt;a href="https://diy-fi.net/"&gt;DIY-Fi&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
This new service fully reimplements DIY's online store for the DS version of the game, bringing back weekly games&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to download, alongside design contests.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="DIY-Fi showing 2025 Halloween contest winners on real hardware" src="./images/doujinsoft/diy-fi.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A design contest popped up for Halloween, so I thought, why not test myself a bit and see if I &lt;em&gt;could make a game without redoing any of the tutorials 14 years later&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;(DoujinSoft now supports &lt;code&gt;iframe&lt;/code&gt; embeds! Feel free to embed all your DIY microgames and comics on your own websites.)&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=a7f667db4362842bee783123cd235699#iframe" width="536" height="490"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...OK, it was still pretty easy. The &lt;em&gt;Game MakerMatic&lt;/em&gt; creation tool within WarioWare DIY isn't massively complex!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to having maintained DoujinSoft for all those years, I never really forgot all the concepts and terminology, so I guess I had a bit of an advantage.&lt;br&gt;
I think the only thing I had to look back up after all this time was how to do randomness?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A review of the MakerMatic in 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it stack up as a game-making tool though? I think it's alright!&lt;br&gt;
You're very constrained, obviously, but that also makes scope creep essentially &lt;strong&gt;impossible&lt;/strong&gt;, which is very nice if all you want to do is bang out a thing in a few days hunched over your Nintendo DS and call it a day.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The palette is a bit low around 32 or so colors, so you end up relying on dithering pretty fast.&lt;br&gt;
While you might think the most limiting think in the MakerMatic is the "point" system that dictates how much pixel art you can cram into the 64 kilobytes of an individual microgame, I think the true thing that kneecaps you is the maximum of &lt;strong&gt;6 AI statements&lt;/strong&gt; per object.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DIY, AI is not a capitalist buzzword for poorly functioning chatbots, but is essentially the equivalent of a &lt;code&gt;if/else&lt;/code&gt; function in normal programming. So broadly speaking, you only have 6 &lt;code&gt;ifs&lt;/code&gt; per object.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine this gets limiting very fast! Combined with the fact each object can only hold &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; boolean variable, any form of complex logic usually ends up eating through your entire &lt;em&gt;15 object&lt;/em&gt; limit.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="A bunch of objects in Doujin-x68k, entirely filling out the point limit!" src="./images/doujinsoft/diy-objects.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now there are some tricks you can employ to maximize your object use -- Offscreen positions can be used as makeshift additional integer variables, you can also rely on the animation system, etc.. But it kinda all comes back to the fact &lt;strong&gt;logic is the biggest limiter&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not allowing the use of the NDS buttons or microphone is also a bit of a missed opportunity - I can understand the mic if you wanted to keep interoperability with the Wii version&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but the D-pad and A/B buttons would've been a great way to mix things up without adding much complexity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also no real random function in DIY - The game itself teaches you to make use of one of its built-in "random placement" functions to act as your RNG by then doing a position check. It's clever! But also kind of hacky!!   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What about... second game???&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;em&gt;SpookOS&lt;/em&gt;, I wanted to actually test those limits and see how much functionality you can cram in a WWDIY microgame.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some pretty impressive DIY creations out there that do &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=e3c8d428afe0c193710bb0258874e7f2"&gt;Anaglyph 3D&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=e44be2dc1cc27af1de4096c28189290c"&gt;multi-room puzzles&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to try my hand at making a game that just crams a bunch of various stuff in.&lt;br&gt;
We're going &lt;strong&gt;maximalist&lt;/strong&gt; baby! It's the &lt;a href="https://www.kartkrew.org/"&gt;Ring Racers&lt;/a&gt; of WarioWare DIY!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=88ba7dd23152109b8712f4a209dd26ef"&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=0f14d0ddc0e6def0b45adbdbb16ccc6f"&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=3d7c9d2797d3ce65c3a2dd84ea70d278"&gt;lot&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=7a1adf1d1e31185bddf1904d59186e00"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=f31e0eb5beefc9336826f92d6a77287b"&gt;DIY microgames&lt;/a&gt; that replicate Windows or computer interfaces already... But most of these are pretty simple, and I love my toy operating systems!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I grabbed the boss template and made a tiny fake OS using graphics from &lt;a href="./funtography.html"&gt;Funtography&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple windows and embedded games/messages.&lt;br&gt;
I'd just traced the graphics as usual for SpookOS, but here I caved in and used &lt;a href="https://www.romhacking.net/utilities/1011/"&gt;mioedit&lt;/a&gt; to import some bitmaps from the computer. This approach isn't perfect due to the palette limitations though, so I still had to do some redrawing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://diy.tvc-16.science/games?id=2124d89e60265d2535101bc58f7a22fb#iframe" width="536" height="490"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there's realistically not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much you can do in DIY...&lt;br&gt;
But I had fun figuring out the balancing act between the various point, AI, and object limits.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make an object blink, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; use a sprite animation... Or you could just rely on two variables to teleport it out of bounds and back in within the same AI statement. Stuff like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with the microgame, so I forcefully sent it to 150 Wii consoles through WiiLink with the yearly DoujinSoft newsletter.&lt;br&gt;
That's the harsh truth of marketing, baby...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="And I get to make a Songs of Innocence joke! phenomenal" src="./images/doujinsoft/wiimb-u2.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I do think there's a bit of a framework here for "zine-like" DIY games, that contain just tiny little bits of text, graphics and maybe showcasing some tricks you can do with the MakerMatic.&lt;br&gt;
Putting together text in the editor on the NDS is &lt;strong&gt;maximum pain&lt;/strong&gt; though, so I don't think that'll happen!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; DoujinSoft has now been running for a longer time that the official Nintendo WFC service did for DIY on Nintendo DS... Also I was rewatching some older Game Center CX episodes and Arino was only 32 at the start of the show?? holy shit&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Before&lt;/strong&gt; it got bought over by yoyo games! can you imagine? I was too young to get into Klik &amp;amp; Play/Multimedia Fusion when it was the &lt;a href="https://jtholen.bandcamp.com/album/new-active-object"&gt;hype gamemaking tool for kids&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; The weekly games are powered by snapshots of the latest additions to the DoujinSoft dataset! It's really cool to see the archive being used in that way.&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Although they &lt;strong&gt;could&lt;/strong&gt; have used waggle/motion controls on the Wii in place of the mic! It'd have been silly but pretty fun if you ask me.&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="nintendo"></category><category term="wii"></category><category term="nintendo ds"></category><category term="warioware"></category><category term="doujinsoft"></category><category term="mio"></category><category term="diy"></category><category term="gamedev"></category></entry><entry><title>I made a Playdate game in two days and it's ok™️</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/sonic-drift-mania.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2024-02-17:/sonic-drift-mania.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;gotta crank it with sonic&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've used this year's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=noOeYcKlTsQ"&gt;Really Amateur Games Expo&lt;/a&gt; as an excuse to finally look at the &lt;a href="https://sdk.play.date"&gt;Playdate SDK&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having two weeks to work on it, I only really spent two days... The advantage of a competition aimed towards making the &lt;strong&gt;worst&lt;/strong&gt; fangame possible is that even if it's rushed and bad, that's the entire point so 👌👌🔥&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="can you believe the game.com version of sonic jam also has blue spheres except due to the screen being grayscale they called it get black spheres and that's where i ripped all of that HUD from" src="./images/playdate/playdate-20240216-163945.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yes it's blue spheres again the world will never be freed of blue spheres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You can download the result .pdx file on itch at the link below. Works on real Playdates!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" src="https://itch.io/embed/2532206" width="552" height="167"&gt;&lt;a href="https://difegue.itch.io/sonic-drift-mania"&gt;Sonic Drift Mania by dfug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only real design idea I had going into this was "you can use the crank to accelerate to &lt;em&gt;ridiculous&lt;/em&gt; speeds":&lt;br&gt;
Making a real platformer with the (self-)alloted time wouldve been difficult, so I settled for a Mode-7 racing game instead, as that's basically just using the builtin &lt;a href="https://sdk.play.date/inside-playdate/#m-graphics.image.drawSampled"&gt;&lt;code&gt;drawSampled&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is nice and all, but the Playdate core library only gives you this, and no other tools to uh, draw other sprites positioned within the mode-7 world...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the spheres are just painted on the track.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="i did this all for u blue spheres guy" src="./images/playdate/playdate-20240216-164054.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
...I actually &lt;strong&gt;tried&lt;/strong&gt; to make them proper objects, okay?!&lt;br&gt;
It's &lt;a href="https://www.coranac.com/tonc/text/mode7.htm"&gt;too much math&lt;/a&gt; for my dumb brain and there was &lt;a href="https://devforum.play.date/t/mode7-screen-coordinate-in-perspective/8751"&gt;nothing&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://devforum.play.date/t/f-time-trial-demo/6989/11"&gt;copypaste&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br&gt;
There's technically a &lt;a href="https://github.com/risolvipro/playdate-mode7"&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; you can import to get full mode7 functionality on Playdate now, but I wanted to just play with the stock SDK here; We ain't making a &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt; game or anything preposterous like that....  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the SDK, very fun to use! It's quite intuitive and gives you a bunch of tools I wouldn't necessarily expect from a low-spec console, like built-in &lt;a href="https://sdk.play.date/2.3.1/#M-json"&gt;JSON deserialization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://sdk.play.date/inside-playdate/#M-sound"&gt;MP3 decoding&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br&gt;
Which you should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; use! It takes like 50% of the CPU on real hardware so you're better off converting to .wav.&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1-bit nature of the playdate screen makes it pretty easy to just grab a &lt;a href="https://www.spriters-resource.com/game_gear/sonicdrift/sheet/79145/"&gt;bunch&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://www.spriters-resource.com/game_com/sonicjam/sheet/79534/"&gt;different&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.textures-resource.com/pc_computer/sonicr/texture/11828/"&gt;assets&lt;/a&gt;, slam them all into aseprite with default dithering&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and boom! &lt;strong&gt;graphics&lt;/strong&gt;! As shrimple as that...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="COOL!" src="images/playdate/playdate-20240216-164047.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; wav files are actually converted to .pda by the playdate compiler, so when using the fileplayer you need to load filenames with the .pda extension for them to play... the sampleplayer doesn't have this problem so you can just throw .wav filenames at it for some reason&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; Or &lt;a href="https://gazs.github.io/canvas-atkinson-dither/"&gt;Atkinson dithering&lt;/a&gt; if you're a nerd (I forgot that was a possibility until writing this..)&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="gamedev"></category><category term="playdate"></category><category term="lua"></category><category term="rage"></category><category term="sage"></category><category term="sonic"></category></entry><entry><title>Original Game Drop: Funtography</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/funtography.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-09-01:/funtography.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Who are you running from?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that &lt;a href="./total-internet-hyperdeath.html"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, the SAGE Double Donk is &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm anxiously excited to release &lt;em&gt;Funtography: A Gameboy Cameradventure&lt;/em&gt;, an actual *gulp* &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; video game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="The SAGE trailer is a pretty cool wallpaper ngl - but you can change it if you want!" src="./images/funtography/ft2.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Check it out at &lt;a href="https://sonicfangameshq.com/forums/showcase/funtography-a-gameboy-cameradventure.1861/"&gt;SAGE 2023&lt;/a&gt;! ... Or itch.io if that's more your speed.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder="0" src="https://itch.io/embed/2243430" width="552" height="167"&gt;&lt;a href="https://difegue.itch.io/funtography-a-gameboy-cameradventure"&gt;Funtography: A Gameboy Cameradventure by dfug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this 2h-long &lt;sub&gt;&lt;em&gt;(1h if ur quick...)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; adventure game, enjoy looking at &lt;strong&gt;100+ Gameboy Camera pictures&lt;/strong&gt; as you explore various urban vistas to solve the mystery of a &lt;em&gt;missing video game prototype&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="No vidcon at tubcon." src="./images/funtography/ft_final2.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
- Four endings!&lt;br&gt;
- Built-in &lt;strong&gt;developer commentary&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
- Unlockable soundtrack!&lt;br&gt;
- &lt;strong&gt;Bonus fake operating system!&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It's got it all!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="i touch on this in the commentary but it's crazy how fast everyone forgot about this olive oil coffee fiasco. hi /agdg/!" src="./images/funtography/ft_final3.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I hope you will consider taking a look at it in the midst of all the good-ass games releasing at SAGE.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept behind this game, &lt;code&gt;Visual novel that uses Gameboy Camera photos with varying palette and borders for extra context&lt;/code&gt; isn't really new&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - I tried building this thing close to &lt;a href="https://github.com/Difegue/shaftboy"&gt;10 years ago&lt;/a&gt; already.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="&amp;quot;Catastrophic project which will likely never get finished&amp;quot;, dated 2014 -- past me been real quiet since this dropped" src="./images/funtography/ft_old.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I had a nice homegrown C++ engine with a barebones scripting system and all, ready to support the story... Then the &lt;em&gt;major blocker&lt;/em&gt; happened:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"what kind of story should I even write, what the shit?"&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="old shaftboy engine prototype screenshot - you can see that TV photo in the final game nowadays at last.." src="./images/funtography/ft_proto.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are natural story-tellers. Our brains are wired for storytelling, both in our enjoyment of experiencing stories, and our ability to create them. This fools us into thinking that storytelling is easy, which it’s not. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;&lt;a href="https://dreamertalin.medium.com/four-failures-1996-2002-5611b955f14"&gt;(Four Failures: 1996-2002)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I shelved the whole thing, with a bunch of art assets, Gameboy photos and """music""" ready to go.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="this screen is from january 2022 god where does the time go" src="images/gamedev/jan_22_screen.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As I was building out this fake operating system that could run self-contained small apps and games, the idea of reviving &lt;em&gt;Funtography&lt;/em&gt; kinda came up on its own.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"If a goal for this fake OS game is to have unlockable smaller games within it... Why shouldn't I just reuse all those old assets I already had?"&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then of course it ballooned out of control as I started writing -- The extra engine work and plot outline were made during the lockdowns after bingewatching &lt;em&gt;Twin Peaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but most of the writing happened this year after work on &lt;a href="./dialogueforest.html"&gt;DialogueForest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  wrapped up.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the result actually stands out on its own length-wise, I wanted to ship it early, as both a &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt; of the existing fake OS&lt;sup id="ref-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;...and hopefully something compelling enough on its own.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="./images/funtography/ft_final4.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Since I'm not really a pro writer, I thought the best I could do would be to make it as earnest/genuine as I could -- Even if it ends up being a bit corny, I hope it at least makes for something more engaging than a ebin ironic story would be.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, I can pretty confidently say it's unique...Which is something I did &lt;a href="./2022-recap.html"&gt;mention wanting to do&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
And it does feel nice to have realized an old concept from years past! &lt;em&gt;I am cringe but I am free.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; Or original for that matter -- Check out &lt;a href="https://pierrec.itch.io/pocket-puppet"&gt;Pocket Puppet&lt;/a&gt; if you want more Cameradventure! It even works on real hardware.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; You can certainly see the influences in the final product - Not as much as I was expecting tho&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; Which of course, I did &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; use while writing Funtography... I relied on &lt;a href="https://videdialogues.wordpress.com"&gt;VIDE Dialogues&lt;/a&gt; for Unity instead as that allowed me to integrate the SFX/palette/border changes better. Still ended up a mess&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-4"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-4"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Slated for release 2035.. I want to keep working on the larger game but I feel some respite knowing that even if I give up on it now, at least some portion of it will have been used. &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="video games"></category><category term="gamedev"></category><category term="unity"></category><category term="c#"></category><category term=".net"></category><category term="gameboy"></category><category term="gameboy camera"></category><category term="faux-OS"></category><category term="sage"></category></entry><entry><title>Total Internet Hyperdeath</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/total-internet-hyperdeath.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-07-02:/total-internet-hyperdeath.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A piece where I, in fact, do not talk about the total internet hyperdeath whatsoever&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, it's been a hot minute! I'm writing this between farming race tickets in Sonic Speed Simulator&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  .&lt;br&gt;
While I'll never give money to anything touching Roblox, I do find some zen in repeatedly boosting away on a Sunday night...&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="roblox have functional lightmaps challenge (impossible)" src="images/speedsim.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So Web 2.0 is having a normal one at the moment or something - A lot of people have waxed poetic about the collapse of the corporate internet already so I don't feel like I could add anything particularly snarky to it...&lt;br&gt;
So how about reading something else? Here are some nice links I've stumbled upon recently.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bylinebyline.com/articles/no-vacancy-hotel"&gt;No Vacancy - A Night at the Motel&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docseuss.medium.com/i-beat-impostor-syndrome-and-heres-how-i-did-it-b6879422af2b"&gt;DocSeuss' 'I beat impostor syndrome (and here's how I did it)'&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/newsletters/sunshine-skyway/"&gt;Robin Sloan - Crossing the Sunshine Skyway&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also found this &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6qJe3rf-VFs"&gt;soundtrack project&lt;/a&gt; for a fictional PS1 megaten game a few days ago - Give it a listen if you're a fellow Devil Summoner enjoyer.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A quick Devlog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've finished up work on Sonic McOrigins' &lt;a href="https://elk.zone/kolektiva.social/@Difegue/110633333584428326"&gt;"Plus" update&lt;/a&gt; for SAGE a few months ago already, so I'm trying to go for a &lt;strong&gt;Double Donk&lt;/strong&gt; and get another game out the door before that deadline hits.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I'm saying game but it's kinda like a demo as well?&lt;br&gt;
This fake OS I've been on-and-off building in Unity has a fair bit of meat to it already, including being able to run entire small applications/subgames.&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="this screen is from january 2022 god where does the time go" src="images/gamedev/jan_22_screen.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So I thought, why not take &lt;strong&gt;another&lt;/strong&gt; old game concept I never finished, and put it &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; this OS?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="images/gamedev/funto_screen1.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And that's how I ended up with this Visual Novel in a multi-window UI like &lt;a href="https://macintoshgarden.org/games/pathways-darkness"&gt;old Mac OS games&lt;/a&gt;... Except it only uses &lt;a href="https://elk.zone/kolektiva.social/@Difegue/110018074118875940"&gt;Gameboy Camera&lt;/a&gt; pictures for its graphics and a terrible soundtrack I scrambled together years ago.&lt;br&gt;
I outlined most of the plot back in 2019, but as Doc said, filling out the blanks between all the setpieces your brain thought was cool... wow it's hard&lt;sup id="ref-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I end up eventually trashing the bigger fake OS game because Unity 2019 falls out of support everywhere or something, it'd be nice to have at least shipped all this work in &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; form.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll catch y'all in another "games i played post" or something later -- I played quake 2 recently and wow it's almost as boring as bluesky  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; 
Speaking of Sonic, I keep forgetting GSC is continuing the &lt;a href="http://whl4u.jp/wh36/gallery/en/#/images/181"&gt;Nendoroid series&lt;/a&gt; with Tails &amp;amp; Knuckles after &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt; -- Wonfes 36 was huge on non-animanga properties in general I wonder what 37 will bring&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; I've always been mad at &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital:_A_Love_Story"&gt;Digital: A Love Story&lt;/a&gt; for showing you fake downloadable games and not having them actually do anything - That's probably one of my largest motivations with this thing. 🥸  &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-3"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-3"&gt;***&lt;/a&gt; To go with the GBCam-piness(heh) of it all, the dialogue toggles different color palettes and borders for the gameboy photos as you progress through... Which makes the writing process take extra longer as I keep comparing color palettes. &lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gamedev"></category><category term="gamedev"></category><category term="faux-OS"></category></entry></feed>