<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Blogopolis - Techoposting</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://tvc-16.science/feeds/techoposting.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://tvc-16.science/</id><updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>My 2026 Hobonichi Techo lineup picks</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/2026-techo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2025-08-28:/2026-techo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stationery suggestions and Cover considerations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/magazine/2026/y26/"&gt;Hobonichi Techo preview season&lt;/a&gt; again!&lt;br&gt;
Here's a list of designs from this year's lineup I find neat™️.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually make those Techoposts at the end of the year when I &lt;a href="./2025-techo.html"&gt;switch my planner&lt;/a&gt;, but most of the time what I bought is long sold out by this point...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I thought this year I'd actually make the post &lt;em&gt;right before sales actually begin&lt;/em&gt; - It also serves as my shopping list as a result instead of having to keep 20 tabs on my desktop! I'm a genius.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not rehosting any images this time around, so make sure you have third-party images allowed in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;An aside about the Techo phone app&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While last year was a pretty good time Yen-wise to buy a planner, this year feels noticeably worse, &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; if you're in the US... I guess you could try using their &lt;a href="https://techoapp.1101.com/en/"&gt;new phone app&lt;/a&gt; instead?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Techo phone app screenshot, Global Release in December 2025" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/images/tx/topen/1755513296640_mag_y26_techoapp_sq_en.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I don't know how I feel about this, it looks a bit more fun than existing offerings like Apple's &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/12/apple-launches-journal-app-a-new-app-for-reflecting-on-everyday-moments/"&gt;Journal&lt;/a&gt; app, but the reason I personally buy those planners is to, yknow, &lt;strong&gt;avoid using a computer&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can't really paste or draw random crap with a phone app and it's one of the reasons I've never really been able to keep up with digital note-taking&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;... I'll still give it a spin just out of curiosity and because &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D3xDw-gBoXM"&gt;Shogo Sakai&lt;/a&gt; is doing the BGM.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assistants look cute, but it's unclear if they're actually AI/LLM shit or not?&lt;br&gt;
If it's just some basic image recognition with prewritten lines, that'd be a breath of fresh air at this point.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on with the recs!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Techo/Planner Covers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc26_inoue/"&gt;Yuichi Inoue - Hana (Flower)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Yuichi Inoue - Hana (Flower)" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/oc26_inoue/prod_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This one is pretty nice and I really dig the yellow accent as you might have realized by how this blog looks.&lt;br&gt;
It's similar to 2020's &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2020/pc/detail_cover/oc20_ochitsuke/"&gt;Ochitsuke cover&lt;/a&gt;, but with a bit more flair. The lavender bookmarks are nice too!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc26_mothersaturn/"&gt;MOTHER - Mr. Saturn (It’s Great)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mr. Saturn lenticular cover" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/oc26_mothersaturn/prod_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There have been a lot of Mr.Saturn themed covers over the years and I somehow haven't bought one yet... But this one is really tempting with the lenticular effect. Forget great, it's &lt;strong&gt;cool&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
It is a bit more expensive than the other covers though; Not to the outrageous level of the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc25_mothernbike/"&gt;leather one from last year&lt;/a&gt;, but still a solid 10€ extra from the flower one, for example.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/cc26_mothersaturn/"&gt;larger A5 variant&lt;/a&gt; with even more lenticular Mr.Saturns!&lt;br&gt;
I always buy the A6 planners, since I don't really write enough (or draw) to fill those huge A5 ones...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc26_jito/"&gt;Junji Ito - Tomie - Knowing Smile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/oc26_jito/prod_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What's up with the material choices this year? I'm not complaining though.&lt;br&gt;
The iridescent/shiny material peeking through works really well with Junji's older artwork on this one, it's giving old mecha anime freezeframe vibes. &lt;sub&gt;Does that make sense? I wish I had an example screenshot on hand but I don't&lt;/sub&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc25_ishikawa/"&gt;Naoki Ishikawa - Denali in the Midnight Sun #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Denali in the Midnight Sun cyanotype cover" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/oc25_ishikawa/prod_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This one is technically from last year, but it's still available and was in my bucket list back then.&lt;br&gt;
I just think cyanotype is really neat! It's also cheaper than the other covers due to being an older design.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inside of the cover is a bit boring, but that doesn't really matter when you're actually using it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_coco_tamagotchi/"&gt;Tamagotchi - Cover on Cover for A6 Size (Growth Chart!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tamagotchi - Cover on Cover" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_coco_tamagotchi/prod_01.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Tamagotchi collab for this year is pretty cool, but I'm not a fan of the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc26_tamagotchi/"&gt;cover design&lt;/a&gt; they put out for it -- It's far too busy and heavy on the pixel art overall... This translucent cover-on-cover though? Pretty good!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are nice alternatives to buying "full" covers, since you can pair them with one of the (comparatively cheap) &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc25_colorswcandle/"&gt;unicolor covers&lt;/a&gt; and mix-and-match however you want.&lt;br&gt;
If you're more money-savvy than I am and don't buy a brand new cover every year, cover-on-covers are nice alternatives to still switch up the design of your Techo every year.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might do something stupid this year and pair this with the Denali cover... It'd be fun, OK? &lt;em&gt;Do you hate fun or something?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Stationery&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_template_moomin/"&gt;Hobonichi Stencil - Moomin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Moomin stencil" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_template_moomin/prod_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
hell yeah I love me some Moomin  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to Tamagotchi, I'm not a fan of the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_cover/oc26_moomin/"&gt;cover design&lt;/a&gt; for this collab, but I'm probably going to grab this stencil so I can mindlessly doodle some Finn creatures in my pages from time to time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_addonfusen_tsuki/"&gt;Add-on Sticky Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Add-on Sticky Notes" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_addonfusen_tsuki/loc_02.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is one of those "holy shit &lt;em&gt;technology&lt;/em&gt;" type of stationery, similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_pocket/"&gt;Pocket Cards&lt;/a&gt; which I'm a huge fan of.&lt;br&gt;
Usually when I write too much I just overflow a bit on the pages of the prior/next day, but being able to just paste an additional sheet like that...what power!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you could do this by just...pasting a bit of paper from wherever into your page and folding it, but it's nice to have a version that uses the exact same paper and grid size.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_cardset_tsuki/"&gt;TSUKI no IRO - Mini Card Set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mini Card Set w/ envelopes" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_cardset_tsuki/loc_01.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Those are just some small cards and matching stickers, more for putting on top of presents than in a planner - I quite like the 70s-ness of the designs though, which is why it's here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like everything in the Tsuki no Iro series though, they're a bit expensive...&lt;br&gt;
Not as bad as "&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_uballset_tsuki/"&gt;64€ for 12 ballpoint pens&lt;/a&gt; what do you MEAN&lt;/em&gt;", but still.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_decorush_2026/"&gt;Deco Rush - Tamagotchi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="holy shit tama roll" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_decorush_2026/prod_03.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Do I even have to say anything?&lt;br&gt;
...Well, I will say that &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_decorush/"&gt;Deco Rush&lt;/a&gt; stickers are surprisingly more annoying to apply than you might think looking at the promo pictures -- You have to press down pretty hard or else they'll usually tear upon application.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_stappo_moomin/"&gt;Stappo - Moomin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/tt_stappo_moomin/prod_01.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have now been shilling the Stappo stationery pouch for three years and will continue to do so as long as they release new banger designs for them.&lt;br&gt;
I almost wish I'd waited before getting mine now that they're putting out those nice versions with necktie fabric and embroidery... alas.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Stappo stationery pouch and pretzel-powered bag of holding" src="images/techo/stappo.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/s_maste/"&gt;Just some washi tape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2026/detail_images/s_maste/prod_01.webp"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Is this a boring one to end with? I dig the fruit/food sticker designs and they're about the price of a TF2 key each so...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also consider the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2026/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_fusen_tamagotchi/"&gt;Tamagotchi sticky notes&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; It's hard enough thinking of something to write every day at times 😤&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Techoposting"></category><category term="techo"></category><category term="hobonichi"></category><category term="stationery"></category><category term="journaling"></category></entry><entry><title>My 2025 Hobonichi Techo picks</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/2025-techo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-12-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2024-12-31:/2025-techo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;time and cringe are social constructs and don't matter&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2024, huh.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usual thought is "&lt;em&gt;wow this year went by in a flash!&lt;/em&gt;" but then I looked at a bunch of photos and went "&lt;em&gt;wait this was in 2024? I thought that was ages ago..&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;br&gt;
All I'm saying is that time is bullshit and shouldn't really matter as much as it does.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since computers are getting &lt;a href="./dialogueforest-msstore.html"&gt;increasingly worse&lt;/a&gt;, I've been continuing to handwrite in my &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/"&gt;Hobonichi Techo&lt;/a&gt; planner.&lt;br&gt;
So as usual, here's what I bought to keep doing that in 2025!&lt;br&gt;
With the current state of the Yen, I think it's pretty accessible at the moment.&lt;sup id="ref-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cover pick for this year is the new &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_cover/oc25_pamm/"&gt;PAMM one&lt;/a&gt; - I missed out on the green one last year, but this new blue variant is a fine alternative. I like squiggly lines! That's &lt;a href="./stylophone-27.html"&gt;just the way it is&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I have to say, it really doesn't fit with the color scheme they picked this year for the Jetstream pen -- What is this, &lt;a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/a-tribute-to-the-windows-31-hot-dog-stand-color-scheme/"&gt;Hot Dog Stand&lt;/a&gt;? I might just keep using my blue 2022 one and swap the ink cartridges or something.   &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="2024 v 2025 techos" src="images/techo/2025.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I picked the Original again instead of the English version - I didn't have any problem with it &lt;a href="./053-2024-techo.html"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; and appreciated the different layout, so might as well keep saving those 500 yen.&lt;sup id="ref-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#note-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other designs I considered this year are the really cool &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_cover/oc25_ishikawa/"&gt;Cyanotype mountain photo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and this Indian &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_cover/oc25_phoolon/"&gt;fabric&lt;/a&gt; cover.&lt;br&gt;
And wow, they finally ran out of &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_cover/oc20_mothertile/"&gt;Mr. Saturn tiles&lt;/a&gt;! I never bought this one in the end.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Stappo stationery pouch and pretzel-powered bag of holding" src="images/techo/stappo.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I didn't really buy any extra stationery this year since I still have a batch I'm going through;&lt;br&gt;
I just bought some new &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_pocket/?recommend"&gt;stick-on pockets&lt;/a&gt; for cards and a few &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_stampset/"&gt;new stamps&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have a &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_stappom_camib"&gt;mini version&lt;/a&gt; of their stationery pouch now though!&lt;br&gt;
I still like my regular-sized one a year in, so you might be interested.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;em&gt;What do I even write in those planners&lt;/em&gt;" you might ask? Usually it's basic food stuff, pasting in cards and tickets, and the occasional gamedev/other idea I have to put down to paper before it &lt;a href="https://artreview.com/daydreaming-is-so-important-to-me-how-david-lynch-fishes-for-ideas/"&gt;vanishes away&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I find it hard to put to paper things you daydream about because... &lt;strong&gt;it's cringe&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
Some of this stuff is dumb feel-good crap, has zero value and will probably never be read again, right?&lt;br&gt;
Even being aware that cringe is made up and doesn't matter, there's always that slight deterrent in the back of your mind.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/magazine/contents/y25_itoi/mnpkrp9nr.html"&gt;yearly Itoi interview&lt;/a&gt; when making my purchases this year, and I found a pretty good answer to that:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a little embarrassing, but then again, I can only feel that way because I wrote it down in the first place.&lt;br&gt;
It’s a feeling I encourage everyone to experience.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I think I'll strive to write even more cringe in 2025.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm always slightly worried about all the semi-blank pages I'm leaving in each year since I'm anything but diligent..&lt;br&gt;
But when you compare the bulgy planner of the last year with the fresh one, I always end up thinking "&lt;em&gt;oh yeah this was a pretty packed year! I think I did good here&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="thick boy on the left" src="images/techo/2025-2.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life goes on and it'll probably be alright.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
...Am I going to manage to work on my goddamn game this year???  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id="note-1"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-1"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt; unless you live in Europe and have atrocious customs fees I guess.. There are also always those outrageously priced luxury covers. I'm shocked they made a &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2025/pc/detail_cover/oc25_mothernbike/"&gt;leather MOTHER 2&lt;/a&gt; one this year, they think Earthbound fans are all megarich socialites or something? I'm trying to envision the final collapse of Capitalism over here!&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;sup id="note-2"&gt;&lt;a href="#ref-2"&gt;**&lt;/a&gt;I'm painfully aware the endgame is probably to raise the price of the original once the other english version gets killed off because low sales or some shit, but while it lasts? I'll take the savings ig&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Techoposting"></category><category term="techo"></category><category term="hobonichi"></category><category term="stationery"></category></entry><entry><title>My 2024 Hobonichi Techo picks</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/2024-techo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-12-20:/2024-techo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy nothing special day!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This wretched year has almost come to an end and I've done my yearly shopping spree on the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/"&gt;Hobonichi Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
I grab a new planner and cover &lt;a href="./2023-techo.html"&gt;each year&lt;/a&gt;, alongside some goodies when the budget allows 🫠  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cover pick for this year is... the Tower of the Sun-inspired &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_cover/oc24_okamoto/"&gt;Golden Mask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; design!&lt;br&gt;
I wanted to get the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_cover/oc24_pamm/"&gt;PAMM collab&lt;/a&gt; design first, but it was out of stock by the time I placed my order.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I like &lt;em&gt;Golden Mask&lt;/em&gt; a bit more in the end though, it's rare to have a cover that flashy.&lt;br&gt;
Other designs of note this year are the mint-accented &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_cover/oc24_checkbk"&gt;Gingham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and the stickerbombed &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_cover/oc24_motherat/"&gt;yearly &lt;em&gt;MOTHER 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; cover.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grabbed a random FGO strap I got as a gift a while back to attach to the pen holder this year -- Mostly because the gold border matches the cover.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="2023 v 2024 techos" src="images/techo/2024.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the major differences this year is that there are &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; versions of the English Techo now; The usual one I've been using for a few years already now (&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/all_about/planner/"&gt;Planner&lt;/a&gt;), and a 1-to-1 translation of the classic Japanese planner (&lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/all_about/original/"&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br&gt;
It's a bit confusing saying it like that, but basically the only major difference is in the daily page layout...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a &lt;em&gt;550 Yen price difference&lt;/em&gt;. Needless to say, I picked the Original this year.&lt;br&gt;
I actually quite like that its page layout has &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/2024/images/all_about/original_about04/zoom_04_2_of_2.jpg"&gt;premade checkmarks&lt;/a&gt; for to-do lists; That's a thing I often do with my daily pages to try and keep my brain organized, so it's a welcome extra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stationery-wise, I wanted to try out the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_stappo_dc/"&gt;stationery pouch&lt;/a&gt; they released last year... I like it a lot! Sure beats the old plastic box I was using to store my washi tapes and stamps.&lt;br&gt;
I also grabbed those &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_toolstoys/s_peta/"&gt;transparent speech bubble stickers&lt;/a&gt;. The adhesive feels super weak when you peel them off but it sticks surprisingly well to paper. Used a few of 'em for christmas cards!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Stappo stationery pouch and pretzel-powered bag of holding" src="images/techo/stappo.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This year's &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/benefit/"&gt;bonus item&lt;/a&gt; is a mini-tote bag you can fit the techo in -- Design is randomly picked out of four and I'm very glad to have gotten the objectively best design out of all of them. 🥨🥨🥨  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was tempted to get the bigass &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2024/pc/detail_toolstoys/tt_stamp_opmdon/"&gt;One Piece onomatopeia stamp&lt;/a&gt; since it's just fun to use huge stamps..&lt;br&gt;
But I've never actually watched or read OP. ¯\_(ツ)_/¯  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Techoposting"></category><category term="techo"></category><category term="hobonichi"></category><category term="stationery"></category></entry><entry><title>My 2023 Hobonichi Techo picks</title><link href="https://tvc-16.science/2023-techo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Difegue</name></author><id>tag:tvc-16.science,2023-01-01:/2023-techo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about buying a techo a year is that I never run out of 3-color ballpens now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New year, new &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/"&gt;Hobonichi Techo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's pick for my planner cover is the &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2023/pc/detail_cover/oc23_shimatsuka/"&gt;Eri Shimatsuka&lt;/a&gt; design. Feels nice going back to a textile cover again, and the ball-shaped bookmarks are particularly lovely.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I pick a random strap doodad from a box I have laying around and attach it to the pen holder;&lt;br&gt;
For this year I've picked this tiny green bag with a mascot character. Fun! I have no idea where it comes from, but the mascot has the same green hue as one of the bookmarks so it's a nice match.      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="k-kawaii..." src="images/techo/2023cover.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The bag can fit &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; small roll of washi tape, so for once this is actually practical and not just extra decoration. I've put one roll of &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2023/pc/detail_toolstoys/s_pavilio/"&gt;Pavilio&lt;/a&gt; in there.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year's techo came with a sampler for the new Tomoe River paper variant that'll be used starting next year: It's noticeably...smoother? Both to the touch and when writing on, which feels nice.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="2022 vs 2023 techo" src="images/techo/2023.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The bundled pen is brown for 2023, which fits the cover and its leather bookmarks nicely as well.&lt;br&gt;
I liked 2022's mint a lot (that's usually the color I pick for the &lt;a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/photos/1082668-earthbound-mother"&gt;window theme&lt;/a&gt; in EarthBound too!), so I'm probably going to keep it around for random note writing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gonna need to put something else in that pen holder to keep the 2022 techo closed though, it's noticeably bulgy this year. 😌  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't get much in the way of new stationery this year -- I tried the new &lt;a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/magazine/tt_report/202209/"&gt;Deco Rush&lt;/a&gt;, and they're quite fun!&lt;br&gt;
They run out quickly, but I feel part of that is because I botched up quite a few times when using them, wasting some of the sticker tape...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For kicks, here are the pictures for the previous years - had to dig a bit in the ol' twitter archives to find those again.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2020 vs 2021 techo" src="images/techo/2021.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="2021 vs 2022 techo" src="images/techo/2022.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Techoposting"></category><category term="techo"></category><category term="hobonichi"></category><category term="stationery"></category></entry></feed>